// autogenerated file - DO NOT EDIT THIS FILE UNDER ANY CIRCUMSTANCES
// OR FACE YOUR DOOM!!
//encoding = RAW

//tagGreeceQ1UiTitle=A Troubled Village{^n}
tagGreeceQ1UiTitle=ヘロス村の災難{^n}
//tagGreeceQ2UiTitle=Spartans at War{^n}
tagGreeceQ2UiTitle=スパルタの戦い{^n}
//tagGreeceQ3UiTitle=The Words of the Oracle{^n}
tagGreeceQ3UiTitle=賢人の言葉{^n}
//tagGreeceQ4UiTitle=The Source of the Monsters{^n}
tagGreeceQ4UiTitle=モンスターの巣{^n}
//tagGreeceQ5UiTitle=The Battle for Athens{^n}
tagGreeceQ5UiTitle=アテネへの戦い{^n}
//tagGreeceQ6UiTitle=The Order of Prometheus{^n}
tagGreeceQ6UiTitle=プロメテウス騎士団{^n}
//tagGreeceQ7UiTitle=Under the Labyrinth{^n}
tagGreeceQ7UiTitle=迷路の奥深く{^n}
//tagGreeceQ7AltUiTitle=The Heart of the Maze{^n}
tagGreeceQ7AltUiTitle=迷宮の中心へ{^n}
//tagEgyptQ8UiTitle=The Blindness of the Gods{^n}
tagEgyptQ8UiTitle=盲目の神々{^n}
//tagEgyptQ9UiTitle=The Invocation{^n}
tagEgyptQ9UiTitle=祈祷{^n}
//tagEgyptQ10UiTitle= Telkine in Egypt{^n}
tagEgyptQ10UiTitle=エジプトのテルキン{^n}
//tagOrientQ11UiTitle=The Sickle of Kronos{^n}
tagOrientQ11UiTitle=クロノスの鎌{^n}
//tagOrientQ12UiTitle=Hunt for the Sickle{^n}
tagOrientQ12UiTitle=伝説の鎌を追い求めて{^n}
//tagOrientQ13UiTitle=Journey to the Jade Palace{^n}
tagOrientQ13UiTitle=翡翠宮殿への旅立ち{^n}
//tagOrientQ14UiTitle=Under Wusao Mountain{^n}
tagOrientQ14UiTitle=武少山の地下{^n}
//tagOlympusQ15UiTitle=Olympus{^n}
tagOlympusQ15UiTitle=天界オリュンポス{^n}

//tagQ1AObjA=Save Timaeus' horse{^n}
tagQ1AObjA=ティマイオスの馬を救え{^n}
//tagQ1AObjB=Speak to Timaeus{^n}
tagQ1AObjB=ティマイオスと話せ{^n}
//tagQ1AObjC=Investigate the problems in Helos{^n}
tagQ1AObjC=ヘロスで事件を調査せよ{^n}
//tagQ1AObjD=Find and defeat the satyr shaman{^n}
tagQ1AObjD=サテュロス シャーマンを 探し出し、倒せ{^n}
//tagQ1AObjE=Return to Diomedes in the village{^n}
tagQ1AObjE=村のディオメデスの 所へ戻れ{^n}
//tagQ1AObjF=Return to the farmer Eumolpus{^n}
tagQ1AObjF=農夫エウモルポスの 所へ戻れ{^n}
//tagQ2ObjA=Find Leonidas in Sparta{^n}
tagQ2ObjA=スパルタのレオニダスを 見つけよ{^n}
//tagQ2ObjB=Defeat the centaur Nessus to gain an audience with Leonidas{^n}
tagQ2ObjB=レオニダスに謁見する ため、ケンタウロス ネッソスを倒せ{^n}
//tagQ2ObjC=Return to the Spartan Camp and tell Brasidas of your victory{^n}
tagQ2ObjC=スパルタ野営地に戻り ブラシダスに勝利を伝えよ{^n}
//tagQ2ObjD=peak with Leonidas{^n}
tagQ2ObjD=レオニダスと話せ{^n}
//tagQ3ObjA=Travel to Delphi and consult the great Oracle there{^n}
tagQ3ObjA=デルフォイへ赴き、 偉大なる巫女に 助言を求めよ{^n}
//tagQ3ObjB=Speak with Timon in Megara{^n}
tagQ3ObjB=メガラの ティモンと話せ{^n}
//tagQ4ObjA=Seek answers through the Parnassus Caves{^n}
tagQ4ObjA=パルナッソス洞窟を 抜け「答え」を見つけよ{^n}
//tagQ4ObjB=Defeat the gorgons{^n}
tagQ4ObjB=ゴルゴンを倒せ{^n}
//tagQ4ObjC=Talk to the woman{^n}
tagQ4ObjC=女性と話せ{^n}
//tagQ5ObjA=Travel to Athens{^n}
tagQ5ObjA=アテネへ行け{^n}
//tagQ5ObjB=Speak with Leonidas at the Athens' gates{^n}
tagQ5ObjB=アテネ城門の レオニダスと話せ{^n}
//tagQ6ObjA=Investigate rumors that monsters have breached the walls of Athens{^n}
tagQ6ObjA=アテネの城壁内に 怪物が侵入したという 噂について調査せよ{^n}
//tagQ6ObjB=Find the entrance to the catacombs in the Athenian Parthenon{^n}
tagQ6ObjB=パルテノン神殿で 地下墓地の入り口を 見つけよ{^n}
//tagQ6ObjC=Stop the monsters in the catacombs{^n}
tagQ6ObjC=地下墓地にいる 怪物を 封じ込めよ{^n}
//tagQ6ObjD=Speak to the old man{^n}
tagQ6ObjD=老人と話せ{^n}
//tagQ7ObjA=Locate and protect the artifact in Knossos{^n}
tagQ7ObjA=クノッソスの秘宝を 探し出し、護れ{^n}
//tagQ7ObjB=Meet the Promethean agent at the Athenian docks{^n}
tagQ7ObjB=アテネの港で プロメテウス騎士団の 代理人と会え{^n}
//tagQ7ObjC=Defeat the Telkine{^n}
tagQ7ObjC=テルキンを倒せ{^n}
//tagQ7ObjD=Speak to Kyros{^n}
tagQ7ObjD=キュロスと話せ{^n}
//tagQ8ObjA=Travel to Rhakotis in Egypt and find Imhotep{^n}
tagQ8ObjA=エジプトのラコティスへ 行き イムホテップを探せ{^n}
//tagQ8ObjB=Retrieve the Scroll of Invocation from the Rhakotis Library{^n}
tagQ8ObjB=祈祷の巻物をラコティス の図書館から 取り戻せ{^n}
//tagQ8ObjC=Bring the Scroll to the Temple of Ptah in Sais{^n}
tagQ8ObjC=巻物をサイスの プタハ神殿に届けよ{^n}
//tagQ8ObjD=Defeat Scarabaeus{^n}
tagQ8ObjD=スカラバエウスを倒せ{^n}
//tagQ8ObjE=Bring the Scroll to Imhotep in Memphis{^n}
tagQ8ObjE=巻物をメンフィスの イムホテップに 届けよ{^n}
//tagQ9ObjA=Obtain the Hand of Balance from Giza{^n}
tagQ9ObjA=ギゼで「調和の手」を 入手せよ{^n}
//tagQ9ObjB=Obtain the Eye of Chaos in the region near the Fayum Oasis{^n}
tagQ9ObjB=ファイユームオアシス 付近で「混沌の眼」を 入手せよ{^n}
//tagQ9ObjC=Bring the Hand and the Eye to Imhotep in Memphis{^n}
tagQ9ObjC=2つの秘宝をメンフィス のイムホテップに届けよ{^n}
//tagQ9ObjD=Defeat the Pharaoh's Honor Guard{^n}
tagQ9ObjD=ファラオの 儀仗兵を倒せ{^n}
//tagQ9ObjE=Defeat Nehebkau{^n}
tagQ9ObjE=ネヘブカウを倒せ{^n}
//tagQ10ObjA=Search for the Telkine in the Valley of the Kings{^n}
tagQ10ObjA=王家の谷で テルキンを探せ{^n}
//tagQ10ObjB=Defeat the Telkine{^n}
tagQ10ObjB=テルキンを倒せ{^n}
//tagQ10ObjC=Take the strange tablet and meet Imhotep in Thebes{^n}
tagQ10ObjC=不思議な刻板を 入手し、テーベの イムホテップに 会え{^n}
//tagQ11ObjA=Travel to Babylon{^n}
tagQ11ObjA=バビロンへ行け{^n}
//tagQ11ObjB=Find and protect the Sickle of Kronos{^n}
tagQ11ObjB=「クロノスの鎌」 を探し出し、護れ{^n}
//tagQ11ObjC=Speak to Feiyan{^n}
tagQ11ObjC=飛燕と話せ{^n}
//tagQ12ObjA=Track the Telkine with the Sickle{^n}
tagQ12ObjA=鎌とテルキンを追え{^n}
//tagQ12ObjB=The Telkine went east on the Silk Road{^n}
tagQ12ObjB=テルキンはシルク ロードを東へ 向かった{^n}
//tagQ12ObjC=The Telkine went towards Chang'an{^n}
tagQ12ObjC=テルキンは 長安へ向かった{^n}
//tagQ12ObjD=A woman in Chang'an is looking for you{^n}
tagQ12ObjD=とある女性が長安で あなたを探している{^n}
//tagQ13ObjA=Travel to the Jade Palace and speak to the Yellow Emperor{^n}
tagQ13ObjA=翡翠宮殿へ行き、 黄帝に会え{^n}
//tagQ14ObjA=Find Wusao Mountain{^n}
tagQ14ObjA=武少山を見つけよ{^n}
//tagQ14ObjB=Find Typhon's Prison{^n}
tagQ14ObjB=テュポンの牢獄を 見つけよ{^n}
//tagQ14ObjD=Defeat the Telkine{^n}
tagQ14ObjD=テルキンを倒せ{^n}
//tagQ15ObjA=Follow Typhon through the portal{^n}
tagQ15ObjA=ポータルを抜け、 テュポンを追え{^n}
//tagQ15ObjB=Kill Typhon{^n}
tagQ15ObjB=テュポンを殺せ{^n}

//tagQ1ADescA=Strange beasts have surrounded a poor man's horse. He needs your help in saving it.{^n}
tagQ1ADescA=不幸な男の馬が 奇妙な怪物に 取り囲まれている。 彼はあなたに 助けを求めている。{^n}
//tagQ1ADescB=Strange beasts were attacking a poor man's horse. The horse is safe now.{^n}
tagQ1ADescB=奇妙な怪物が 馬を襲っていたが、 もう安全だ。{^n}
//tagQ1ADescC=The man said that his village, Helos, which is farther down the road, is having trouble with these monsters.{^n}
tagQ1ADescC=この道の先、 あの男の住む ヘロスという村が、 怪物どもに 苦しめられて いるそうだ。{^n}
//tagQ1ADescD=A powerful satyr shaman has been leading boars and satyrs into the village farm land. These monsters threaten to destroy the crops for the entire village and shatter their weakening defenses.{^n}
tagQ1ADescD=強大な力を持つ サテュロス シャーマンが、 猪とサテュロスを率いて 村の農場に 侵入した。 怪物どもは 村の蓄えを 焼き払い、 脆い守備陣を 粉砕せんと している。{^n}
//tagQ1ADescE=A powerful satyr shaman was leading boars and satyrs into the village farmland. These monsters threatened to destroy the crops for the entire village and shatter their frail defenses. With the shaman gone, the village of Helos should be able to hold out against these strange monsters.{^n}
tagQ1ADescE=強大な力を持つ サテュロス シャーマンが、 猪とサテュロスを率いて 村の農場に 侵入した。 怪物どもは 村の蓄えを 焼き払い、 脆弱な守備陣を 粉砕せんと していた。 シャーマンが 死んだので、 ヘロスの村は 怪物どもに 耐えることが できるはずだ。{^n}
//tagQ1DescComplete=A powerful satyr shaman was leading boars and satyrs into the village farmland. These monsters threatened to destroy the crops for the entire village and shatter their frail defenses. With the shaman gone, the village of Helos should be able to hold out against these strange monsters. Long enough, hopefully, for help from the Spartans to arrive.{^n}
tagQ1DescComplete=強大な力を持つ サテュロス シャーマンが、 猪とサテュロスを率いて 村の農場に 侵入した。 怪物どもは 村の蓄えを 焼き払い、 脆弱な守備陣を 粉砕せんと していた。 シャーマンが 死んだので、 ヘロスの村は 持ち直した。 スパルタから援軍が 来るまでの間、 怪物どもに 対しても 十分に持ち こたえることが できるはずだ。{^n}
//tagQ2DescA=Find the great Spartan general, Leonidas, and beg him to send soldiers to protect the village Helos. Perhaps he will also know more of the strange monsters, and where they come from. Travel through Laconia and on to Sparta.{^n}
tagQ2DescA=スパルタの宿将 レオニダス将軍を 捜し出し、 ヘロスを 守護するための 兵士の派遣を 請願せよ。 ことによると、 彼は怪物どもの 素性や由来について もっとよく 知っている かもしれない。 ラコニアを経由し、 スパルタへ行け。{^n}
//tagQ2DescComplete=Leonidas has pledged to send some Spartan warriors to the village. He does not know where the monsters are coming from, but told you to go to the Oracle of Delphi for answers.{^n}
tagQ2DescComplete=レオニダス将軍は スパルタ兵による ヘロス救援を 約束した。 怪物がどこから 来たのかは 知らなかったが、 あなたに デルフォイの巫女に 会うように 告げた。{^n} //tagQ2DescAlt=It is long after you first left the village of Helos. Diomedes and his people have stood or fallen on their own. In the meantime, Leonidas and the Spartan forces have traveled to Athens.{^n}
tagQ2DescAlt=ヘロスを発ってから 随分と時が過ぎた。 ディオメデスと 村民たちは 独力で立ち向かっている。 一方、 レオニダス将軍と スパルタ軍は アテネへと向かった。{^n}
//tagQ3DescA=Leonidas has sent you to the great Oracle in the Temple of Apollo in Delphi to seek help in stopping the monster plague.{^n}
tagQ3DescA=レオニダス将軍の 言葉に従い、 デルフォイへと 向かった。 アポロン神殿の 巫女に会い、 この怪物騒動を 鎮めるための 助言を得るのだ。{^n}
//tagQ3DescAalt=In Megara, a man named Timon suggested that you should consult the great Oracle in the Temple of Apollo in Delphi in order to learn the cause of this monster invasion – and hopefully how to stop it.{^n}
tagQ3DescAalt=メガラの ティモンという男が、 怪物どもの 侵入の原因と、 あわよくばそれを 阻止する方法を 学ぶため、 デルフォイの アポロン神殿の巫女に 相談するよう 勧めた。{^n}
//tagQ3DescComplete=The Oracle delivered not just a prophecy, but a clue – to discover the source of the monsters, you must travel through the Parnassus Caves, which are not far from Delphi.{^n}
tagQ3DescComplete=巫女は予言だけでなく、 怪物騒動の 根源を探る 手がかりを 与えてくれた。 そのためには、 デルフォイに程近い パルナッソス洞窟を 通り抜けねば ならない。{^n}
//tagQ4DescA=The Oracle revealed that the source of the monsters could be learned by traveling through the Parnassus Caves, near Delphi. What could lie beyond?{^n}
tagQ4DescA=巫女は、 パルナッソス洞窟を 抜ければ 怪物騒動の 根源がわかると 言った。 この先に 何があるの だろうか？{^n}
//tagQ4DescB=The Oracle revealed that the source of the monsters could be learned beyond the Parnassus Caves, where a vast war-camp has been established – for an army of monsters!{^n}
tagQ4DescB=巫女は、 パルナッソス洞窟の 向こうで 怪物騒動の 根源がわかると 言った。 そこには 広大な野営地が 設営されていた。 怪物どもの 大軍だ！{^n}
//tagQ4DescC=The Oracle revealed that the source of the monsters could be learned beyond the Parnassus Caves, where a vast war-camp has been established – for an army of monsters. A frightened beggar who was hiding says at the end of the camp is another cave guarded by three great gorgons.{^n}
tagQ4DescC=巫女は、 パルナッソス洞窟の 向こうで 怪物騒動の 根源がわかると 言った。 そこには 広大な野営地が 設営されていた。 怪物どもの 大軍だ。 身をひそめて 怯えていた 乞食によれば、 野営地の奥に 3匹の巨大な ゴルゴンに 守られた 洞窟があるという。{^n}
//tagQ4DescD=The Oracle revealed that the source of the monsters could be learned beyond the Parnassus Caves, where a vast war-camp has been established – for an army of monsters. When the three gorgon queens were slain, a mysterious woman, half turned to stone, was released from their spell.{^n}
tagQ4DescD=巫女は、 パルナッソス洞窟の 向こうで 怪物騒動の 根源がわかると 言った。 そこには 広大な野営地が 設営されていた。 怪物どもの 大軍だ。 3匹のゴルゴン クィーンを 倒すと、 謎の女性に かけられていた 石化の呪いが 解けた。{^n}
//tagQ4DescComplete=The Oracle revealed that the source of the monsters could be learned beyond the Parnassus Caves, where a vast war-camp has been established – for an army of monsters. When the three gorgon matriarchs were slain, a mysterious woman, half turned to stone, was released from their spell. She claimed that the monsters were all summoned by a powerful sorcerer called a Telkine.{^n}
tagQ4DescComplete=巫女は、 パルナッソス洞窟の 向こうで 怪物騒動の 根源がわかると 言った。 そこには 広大な野営地が 設営されていた。 怪物どもの 大軍だ。 3匹のゴルゴン クィーンを 倒すと、 謎の女性に かけられていた 石化の呪いが 解けた。 その女性が 言い立てるには、 これらの 怪物どもは全て テルキンという 強大な妖術師に 召還された ものだと いうのだ。{^n}
//tagQ5DescA=A dark sorcerer known as a Telkine is leading a monster army towards Athens. Whatever his goal, Athens will need all the help it can get.{^n}
tagQ5DescA=テルキンとして知られる 暗黒の魔術師は、 アテネに 怪物の大軍を 差し向けている。 彼奴の目的が 何であれ、 アテネは 喉から手が 出るほど 援軍を欲して いるはずだ。{^n}
//tagQ5DescB=A dark sorcerer known as a Telkine is leading a monster army towards Athens. Even now, Leonidas stands before the gates of Athens with the Spartan forces. He will want to hear news of the Oracle's prophecy and the Parnassus war-camp.{^n}
tagQ5DescB=テルキンとして知られる 暗黒の魔術師は、 アテネに 怪物の大軍を 差し向けている。 今しもレオニダスは、 スパルタ軍とともに アテネの城門を 守っている。 彼は神託の予言と パルナッソスの 怪物野営地の 情報を心待ちに しているだろう。{^n}
//tagQ5DescComplete=After telling Leonidas about the Telkine and the Oracle's prophecy, he spoke of his army's failure in Sparta, and how he is working to unite the armies of Greece. He also spoke of a great battle with the Telkine before the gates of Athens. Halfway through the battle, the dark sorcerer mysteriously vanished.{^n}
tagQ5DescComplete=レオニダスに テルキンの情報と 神託の予言について 伝えると、 彼はスパルタ軍が 敗れたことと、 彼が今 全ギリシャ 連合軍の 結成に心血を 注いでいる ことを語った。 彼はまた、 アテネ城門での テルキンとの 激戦についても 語った。 奇妙なことに、 その暗黒の 魔術師は、戦いのさなかに 突然姿を 消したという。{^n}
//tagQ6DescA=Leonidas has heard reports of monsters within the city walls of Athens. Head into the city and find out how the monsters got in.{^n}
tagQ6DescA=レオニダスは アテネ城内に怪物が 侵入したという 報告を受けた。 街へ行き、 怪物どもが どうやって 侵入したのか 調べよ。{^n}
//tagQ6DescB=Leonidas has heard reports of monsters within the city walls of Athens. A panicked man on the acropolis steps claims that they come from atop the Parthenon, and they are searching for someone in the catacombs beneath it.{^n}
tagQ6DescB=レオニダスは アテネ城内に怪物が 侵入したという 報告を受けた。 アクロポリスの 石段で 狼狽している 男によれば、 奴らはパルテノンの 頂からやって来て、 地下墓地で 誰かを探して いるらしい。{^n}
//tagQ6DescComplete=The monsters in the catacombs were after an ancient brotherhood called the Order of Prometheus. Their leader, Phaedrus, said they have fought forces like the Telkine since nearly the beginning of time.{^n}
tagQ6DescComplete=地下墓地の怪物どもは、 プロメテウス 騎士団と 呼ばれる、 太古の 友愛結社を 追っていた。 その指導者 パイドロスによると、 彼らは有史以来、 テルキンのような 悪と戦って きたのだ という。{^n}
//tagQ7DescA=The Order of Prometheus claims the Telkine is headed for the island of Crete. There, beneath the Palace of Knossos, lies an ancient artifact which connects the realm of man to the realm of the gods. Without this artifact, the gods will be blind to all that is happening beneath the heavens. The Telkine must be stopped before he reaches the artifact.{^n}
tagQ7DescA=プロメテウス騎士団の 言によれば、 テルキンは クレタ島へ 向かったという。 クノッソス宮殿の 地下には、 人間界と 天界とを 結ぶ古代の 秘宝がある。 この秘宝がないと、 神々は地上の 出来事を 何も知ることが できないのだ。 テルキンが 秘宝を入手 する前に、 彼奴を阻止 しなければ ならない。{^n}
//tagQ7DescB=You have defeated the Telkine, but the conduit between the realm of man and the realm of the gods has been destroyed. The Promethean, Kyros, must have followed you from Athens. He has opened a secret exit from the chamber.{^n}
tagQ7DescB=テルキンは倒したが、 人間界と 天界とを 結ぶ導管が 破壊されて しまった。 プロメテウス信徒 キュロスは、 アテネから あなたを 追ってきたの だろう。 隠し扉を 開けてくれた。{^n}
//tagQ7DescComplete=The Telkine was defeated, but the conduit between the realm of man and the realm of the gods has been destroyed. The gods can no longer hear the cries of mortals... or see their plight.{^n}
tagQ7DescComplete=テルキンは敗れたが、 人間界と 天界とを 結ぶ導管が 破壊されて しまった。 もはや神々は、 人々の嘆きに 耳を貸すことも、 地上の苦境を 目にする ことも出来なく なった。{^n}
//tagQ8DescA=The Order of Prometheus has asked you to seek the Egyptian sage Imhotep. They believe he be may be able to restore the connection to the godly realm.{^n}
tagQ8DescA=プロメテウス騎士団から、 エジプトの賢人 イムホテップを 捜すよう 依頼された。 彼になら、 天界との交信を 復旧することが できるかも しれない からだ。{^n}
//tagQ8DescB=Imhotep has asked you to retrieve the Scroll of Invocation from the library in Rhakotis. This scroll may tell how to restore the connection between the mortal and godly realms. He said he would be waiting for you at the Temple of Ptah, near Sais.{^n}
tagQ8DescB=賢人イムホテップに、 ラコティスの 図書館から 祈祷の巻物を 持ち出すよう 頼まれた。 この巻物から 人間界と 天界との 交信を復旧 するための 方法がわかる かもしれない。 彼はサイスの プタハ神殿で 待っている と言った。{^n}
//tagQ8DescC=Imhotep has asked you to retrieve the Scroll of Invocation from the library in Rhakotis. This scroll may tell how to restore the connection between the mortal and godly realms. The Temple of Ptah, where you were to meet Imhotep, has been destroyed!{^n}
tagQ8DescC=賢人イムホテップに、 ラコティスの 図書館から 祈祷の巻物を 持ち出すよう 頼まれた。 この巻物から 人間界と 天界との 交信を復旧 するための 方法がわかる かもしれない。 だが、 イムホテップと 会うはずだった プタハ神殿は 破壊されて しまっていた！{^n}
//tagQ8DescD=There is a second Telkine in Egypt, and it has attacked the Promethean Temple of Ptah, in Sais. It appears Imhotep escaped unharmed, and traveled on to Memphis. Seek him there.{^n}
tagQ8DescD=エジプトに 2体目の テルキンが現れ、 サイスで プロメテウス 信徒の守る プタハ神殿を 襲撃した。 イムホテップは 無傷で逃げ 延びたようだ。 メンフィスへ行き、 彼を探せ。{^n}
//tagQ8DescE=The ancient Scroll of Invocation was kept safe deep beneath the Rhakotis Library. Perhaps with this scroll, Imhotep could restore the connection between the godly and mortal realms.{^n}
tagQ8DescE=いにしえの 祈祷の巻物は、 ラコティス 図書館の 最下層に 安置されていた。 この巻物があれば、 イムホテップは 人間界と 天界との 交信を復旧 することが できるだろう。{^n}
//tagQ8DescF=The ancient Scroll of Invocation was kept safe deep beneath the Rhakotis Library. Perhaps with this scroll, Imhotep could restore the connection between the godly and mortal realms. It appears that the Temple of Ptah, near Sais, was attacked, and Imhotep has fled to Memphis.{^n}
tagQ8DescF=いにしえの 祈祷の巻物は、 ラコティス 図書館の 最下層に 安置されていた。 この巻物があれば、 イムホテップは 人間界と 天界との 交信を復旧 することが できるだろう。 サイスの プタハ神殿が 襲撃され、 イムホテップは メンフィスへ 逃れたようだ。{^n}
//tagQ8DescComplete=There is a second Telkine in Egypt, and it has attacked the Promethean Temple of Ptah, in Sais. Fortunately Imhotep is safe, and the Scroll of Invocation is now in his hands. He seems fervent in his belief that the invocation ceremony will reestablish contact with the gods.{^n}
tagQ8DescComplete=エジプトに 2体目の テルキンが現れ、 サイスで プロメテウス 信徒の守る プタハ神殿を 襲撃した。 幸いイムホテップは 無事で、 祈祷の巻物も 彼の手元にある。 彼は、 祈祷の儀式で 神々との 交信を復旧 するという、 確たる信念を 抱いている。{^n}
//tagQ9DescA=In order for Imhotep to reconnect the mortal and the godly realms, two powerful ancient artifacts, the Hand of Balance and the Eye of Chaos, must be recovered.{^n}
tagQ9DescA=イムホテップが 人間界と天界とを 再びつなぐ ためには、 強力な力を 有する2つの 古代の秘宝 「調和の手」と 「混沌の眼」を 捜し出さねば ならない。{^n}
//tagQ9DescComplete=The invocation ceremony has failed. A new conduit could not be forged, and while a second Telkine plagues Egypt, the gods are beyond all reach.{^n}
tagQ9DescComplete=祈祷の儀式は 失敗に終わった。 新たな導管を 鍛造することは できなかった。 第2のテルキンが エジプトを 苦しめても、 神々には もはや手も 足も出ない。{^n}
//tagQ10DescA=A powerful Telkine has been attacking Promethian Temples throughout Egypt in search of something. The only untouched site still guarded by the Promethians is the tomb of Ramses in the Valley of the Kings, near Thebes. Find and defeat the Telkine.{^n}
tagQ10DescA=強大なテルキンは、 何かを探して エジプト中の プロメテウス 信徒の神殿を 襲撃している。 まだプロメテウスの 信徒によって 守られている 唯一無傷の神殿は、 王家の谷の ラムセスの 墓所だけだ。 テルキンを 捜し出し、 倒せ。{^n}
//tagQ10DescB=The Telkine was searching for an ancient artifact that was believed to be held in a Promethian Temple in Egypt. Upon its death, it dropped a tablet covered with strange writing. Return to Imhotep with the mysterious tablet.{^n}
tagQ10DescB=テルキンはエジプトで、 プロメテウス信徒の 神殿に保管 されていると 信じられていた 古代の秘宝を 探していた。 テルキンは 死ぬとき、 奇妙な文字で 埋め尽くされた 刻板を落とした。 イムホテップに その謎の 刻板を届けよ。{^n}
//tagQ10DescComplete=Your triumph over the Telkine in Egypt is darkened by the news that a third Telkine is now in Babylon. Its purpose seems to be explained by the strange clay tablet you found, which tells of an ancient weapon of great power in Babylon's Hanging Gardens.{^n}
tagQ10DescComplete=エジプトでテルキンに 勝利した喜びは、 バビロンに 第3のテルキンが 現れたという 報せで暗転する。 その目的は、 謎の粘土板に 記されていた、 バビロンの 空中庭園にある 強力な古代の 武器らしい。{^n}
//tagQ11DescA=A third Telkine is now in Babylon searching for the Sickle of Kronos. Use the Scepter of Eternity that Imhotep forged from the Hand of Balance and the Eye of Chaos to create a portal in the Temple of Hatshepsut. This portal will take you to Babylon.{^n}
tagQ11DescA=第3のテルキンは、 バビロンで クロノスの鎌を 探している。 イムホテップが 「調和の手」と 「混沌の眼」から 鍛造した 「不滅の錫杖」を 使えば、 ハトシェプスト神殿の ポータルを開く ことができる。 ポータルを 抜ければ、 そこはバビロンだ。{^n}
//tagQ11DescB=A third Telkine is now in Babylon searching for the Sickle of Kronos. The Telkine may already its location. Time is of the essence.{^n}
tagQ11DescB=第3のテルキンは、 バビロンで クロノスの鎌を 探している。 テルキンは既に 在り処を 見つけたかも しれない。 時間との勝負だ。{^n}
//tagQ11DescC=The Telkine is already in the Hanging Gardens of Babylon! According to the tablet, the Sickle of Kronos lies in the Temple of Marduk, atop the Gardens. If he finds it, the Telkine will then wield great and terrible power.{^n}
tagQ11DescC=テルキンはもう バビロンの 空中庭園にいる！  刻板によれば、 クロノスの鎌は 庭園最上層の マルドゥク 神殿にある。 彼奴がそれを 手にしたら、 恐るべき力を 得ることになる。{^n}
//tagQ11DescD=It appears the Telkine reached the Sickle first. Both are gone, and Feiyan is lying in the Sickle Room, injured, on the floor.{^n}
tagQ11DescD=どうやらテルキンに 先を越されたらしい。 保管庫には 鎌もテルキンの 姿もなく、 怪我を負った 飛燕が 横たわっている。{^n}
//tagQ11DescComplete=It appears the Telkine reached the Sickle first. Feiyan tracked him to Babylon, but was not strong enough to stop him. The Telkine took the Sickle and used it to blast an exit through the east wall. Where is he headed?{^n}
tagQ11DescComplete=どうやらテルキンに 先を越されたらしい。 飛燕が彼奴を バビロンまで 追ってきたのだが、 彼奴を 食い止めるには 力不足だった。 テルキンは 鎌を用い、 東壁を吹き 飛ばして 脱出した。 どこへ向かった のだろう？{^n}
//tagQ12DescA=The Telkine has stolen the Sickle of Kronos and headed eastward, leaving Feiyan injured. You must track the Telkine, learn his goal, and stop him.{^n}
tagQ12DescA=テルキンは クロノスの 鎌を奪い、 負傷した飛燕を 打ち捨てて 東へ向かった。 テルキンを追い、 彼奴の目的を暴き、 阻止せねば ならない。{^n}
//tagQ12DescB=The Telkine stole the Sickle of Kronos and headed eastward. Feiyan is injured; you must track the Telkine, learn his goal, and stop him… The Telkine travels east along the Silk Road, his purpose unknown.{^n}
tagQ12DescB=テルキンは クロノスの 鎌を奪い、 東へ向かった。 飛燕は怪我を 負っているが、 テルキンを追い、 彼奴の目的を暴き、 阻止せねば…。 テルキンは シルクロードを 東へ向かって いるが、 その目的は 不明だ。{^n}
//tagQ12DescC=The Telkine stole the Sickle of Kronos and headed eastward. Feiyan is injured; you must track the Telkine, learn his goal, and stop him… The Telkine was headed towards an Eastern city named Chang'an, his purpose unknown.{^n}
tagQ12DescC=テルキンは クロノスの 鎌を奪い、 東へ向かった。 飛燕は怪我を 負っているが、 テルキンを追い、 彼奴の目的を暴き、 阻止せねば…。 テルキンは 長安という 東方の町に 向かっていた。 その目的は 不明だ。{^n}
tagQ12DesC=テルキンは クロノスの 鎌を奪い、 東へ向かった。 飛燕は怪我を 負っているが、 テルキンを追い、 彼奴の目的を暴き、 阻止せねば…。 テルキンは 長安という 東方の町に 向かっていた。 その目的は 不明だ。{^n}
//tagQ12DescComplete=The Telkine stole the Sickle of Kronos and fled to the East. Feiyan, who reached Chang'an quickly by sea, says the Telkine simply vanished when it got to the city. The Prometheans are at a loss. What can unravel this mystery?{^n}
tagQ12DescComplete=テルキンは クロノスの鎌を奪い、 東へ逃げた。 船便でいち早く 長安へ到達した 飛燕によれば、 テルキンは 街に着くなり 姿を消したという。 プロメテウスの 信徒たちも 行方をつかみ かねている。 どうすれば この謎が 解けるの だろう？{^n}
//tagQ13DescA=Feiyan claims the Yellow Emperor may know where the Telkine went. Legend states that the emperor lives in a jade palace at the top of Mount Qiyun – few mortals have been admitted to the palace.{^n}
tagQ13DescA=飛燕は、 黄帝がテルキンの 行方を知っている はずだと言う。 伝説によると、 黄帝は齊雲山頂の 翡翠宮殿に 住まって いるという。 この宮殿に 足を踏み 入れた人間は ほとんどない。{^n}
//tagQ13DescB=The Yellow Emperor said that the Telkine has gone to Wusao Mountain to free the Titan, Typhon, from his prison there. Feiyan may know the location of this mountain.{^n}
tagQ13DescB=黄帝が言うには、 テルキンは 牢獄のタイタン、 テュポンを 解き放つため、 武少山へと 向かっている。 飛燕なら その山の 場所を知って いるかも しれない。{^n}
//tagQ14DescA=The Telkine plans to use the Sickle to sever the adamantine chains binding the great Titan, Typhon, who is imprisoned beneath Wusao Mountain. If he succeeds, this terrible enemy of the gods will be unleashed on the world. Feiyan will know how to reach the mountain.{^n}
tagQ14DescA=テルキンは、 武少山地下に 収監されている タイタン、 テュポンを 拘束している 堅牢無比な鎖を、 鎌を用いて 断ち切る つもりだ。 そうなれば、 神々の 恐るべき敵が、 この世に 解き放たれて しまう。 飛燕が山へ 行く道を 知っている。{^n}
//tagQ14DescB=The Telkine plans to use the Sickle to sever the adamantine chains binding the great Titan, Typhon, who is imprisoned beneath Wusao Mountain. If he succeeds, this terrible enemy of the gods will be unleashed on the world. Wusao Mountain lies beyond the Forest of the Ancients at the outskirts of Chang'an.{^n}
tagQ14DescB=テルキンは、 武少山地下に 収監されている タイタン、 テュポンを 拘束している 堅牢無比な鎖を、 鎌を用いて 断ち切る つもりだ。 そうなれば、 神々の 恐るべき敵が、 この世に 解き放たれて しまう。 武少山は 長安郊外の 太古の森の 向こうだ。{^n}
//tagQ14DescComplete=The Telkine planned to use the Sickle to sever the adamantine chains binding the great Titan, Typhon, who is imprisoned beneath Wusao Mountain. If he succeeds, this terrible enemy of the gods will be unleashed on the world. Although the Telkine is slain, Typhon was freed, and has gone through a portal of his own making.{^n}
tagQ14DescComplete=テルキンは、 武少山地下に 収監されている タイタン、 テュポンを 拘束している 堅牢無比な鎖を、 鎌を用いて 断ち切る つもりだ。 そうなれば、 神々の 恐るべき敵が、 この世に 解き放たれて しまう。 テルキンは 倒したものの、 テュポンは 解き放たれ、 自ら開いた ポータルを 抜けていって しまった。{^n}
//tagQ15DescA=Typhon has gone to Olympus, seeking revenge on the gods who spitefully imprisoned him beneath Wusao Mountain for thousands of years. He must be stopped.{^n}
tagQ15DescA=テュポンは、 数千年もの間 己を武少山地下に 幽閉した 意地悪な 神々への 復讐を果たさんと、 オリュンポスへ 向かった。 彼奴を食い 止めねば ならない。{^n}

//tagRumorDefaultText=Side Quest Log is Empty{^n}
tagRumorDefaultText=サイドクエストの記録はありません{^n}
//tagRumorGr1Title=Medicines Waylaid{^n}
tagRumorGr1Title=届かない薬{^n}
//tagRumorGr1bTitle=Monstrous Brigands{^n}
tagRumorGr1bTitle=奇怪な山賊{^n}
//tagRumorGr2Title=The Cornered Man{^n}
tagRumorGr2Title=追い詰められた男{^n}
//tagRumorGr3Title=The Lost Dowry{^n}
tagRumorGr3Title=失われた花嫁道具{^n}
//tagRumorGr4Title=The Ancient of War{^n}
tagRumorGr4Title=老兵{^n}
//tagRumorGr5Title=The Poisoned Spring{^n}
tagRumorGr5Title=侵された泉{^n}
//tagRumorGr6Title=Skeleton Raiders{^n}
tagRumorGr6Title=スケルトン レイダー{^n}
//tagRumorGr7Title=Goods Abandoned{^n}
tagRumorGr7Title=棄てられた商品{^n}
//tagRumorGr8Title=News of a Shipwreck{^n}
tagRumorGr8Title=難破の知らせ{^n}
//tagRumorGr9Title=The Good Centaur{^n}
tagRumorGr9Title=善良なケンタウロス{^n}
//tagRumorGr10Title=A Master Blacksmith{^n}
tagRumorGr10Title=鍛冶の名人{^n}
//tagRumorGr11Title=The Grieving Widow{^n}
tagRumorGr11Title=嘆きの未亡人{^n}
//tagRumorGr12Title=Trapped in the Ruins{^n}
tagRumorGr12Title=遺跡の罠{^n}
//tagRumorGr13Title=Spartans Lost{^n}
tagRumorGr13Title=行方不明のスパルタ兵{^n}
//tagRumorGr14Title=A Proper Offering{^n}
tagRumorGr14Title=適切な供物{^n}
//tagRumorGr15Title=Monsters in the Market{^n}
tagRumorGr15Title=市場の怪物{^n}
//tagRumorGr16Title=Xanthippus the Healer{^n}
tagRumorGr16Title=治療師クサンティッポス{^n}
//tagRumorGr17Title=The Undead Tyrant{^n}
tagRumorGr17Title=不死の暴君{^n}
//tagRumorEg1Title=The Family Heirloom{^n}
tagRumorEg1Title=伝家の宝剣{^n}
//tagRumorEg2Title=The Beast of Legend{^n}
tagRumorEg2Title=伝説の獣{^n}
//tagRumorEg3Title=A Promethean Surrounded{^n}
tagRumorEg3Title=包囲されたプロメテウス信徒{^n}
//tagRumorEg4Title=Plight of the Nile Farmers{^n}
tagRumorEg4Title=ナイル農民の苦境{^n}
//tagRumorEg5Title=Lowest of the Low{^n}
tagRumorEg5Title=最下層の住民{^n}
//tagRumorEg6Title=The High Priest's Request{^n}
tagRumorEg6Title=高僧の依頼{^n}
//tagRumorEg7Title=The Missing Brother{^n}
tagRumorEg7Title=行方不明の弟{^n}
//tagRumorEg8Title=Khufu's Curse{^n}
tagRumorEg8Title=クフ王の呪い{^n}
//tagRumorEg9Title=A Hidden Treasure{^n}
tagRumorEg9Title=隠された財宝{^n}
//tagRumorEg10Title=Caravan Woes{^n}
tagRumorEg10Title=キャラバンの悲哀{^n}
//tagRumorEg11Title=The Corrupted Priest{^n}
tagRumorEg11Title=堕ちた僧侶{^n}
//tagRumorOr0Title=A Gargantuan Yeti{^n}
tagRumorOr0Title=巨大なイエティ{^n}
//tagRumorOr1Title=The Seeds of Destruction{^n}
tagRumorOr1Title=破壊の種子{^n}
//tagRumorOr2Title=Neanderthal Shaman{^n}
tagRumorOr2Title=ネアンデルタールの呪術師{^n}
//tagRumorOr3Title=Mystery in the Mountains{^n}
tagRumorOr3Title=山の神秘{^n}
//tagRumorOr4Title=The Village Temple{^n}
tagRumorOr4Title=村の寺院{^n}
//tagRumorOr5Title=Caravan in Trouble{^n}
tagRumorOr5Title=キャラバンの災難{^n}
//tagRumorOr6Title=A Lesson in Despair{^n}
tagRumorOr6Title=絶望から得るもの{^n}
//tagRumorOr7Title=The Child and the Raptor{^n}
tagRumorOr7Title=子どもと猛獣{^n}
//tagRumorOr8Title=Peng Problems{^n}
tagRumorOr8Title=ペンを倒せ{^n}
//tagRumorOr10Title=The Wealthy Collector{^n}
tagRumorOr10Title=裕福な収集家{^n}
//tagRumorOr11Title=Stalker in the Woods{^n}
tagRumorOr11Title=森の追跡者{^n}
//tagRumorOr12Title=The Emperor's Clay Soldiers{^n}
tagRumorOr12Title=皇帝の土人形{^n}
//tagRumorOr13Title=Terra Cottas At Large{^n}
tagRumorOr13Title=兵馬俑の大群{^n}
//tagRumorOr14Title=Behind the Waterfall{^n}
tagRumorOr14Title=滝の裏側{^n}
//tagRumorOr15Title=The Hermit Mage{^n}
tagRumorOr15Title=隠者の魔術師{^n}
//tagRumorOr16Title=Three Sisters{^n}
tagRumorOr16Title=３人姉妹{^n}
//tagRumorOr17Title=A General in Repose{^n}
tagRumorOr17Title=将軍の休息{^n}

//tagRumorGr1DescA=A shepherd came running up to Helos. Monsters had attacked him as he led his flock home from pasture. They grabbed his friend, Tellis, and dragged him into a cave by the roadside. Find the nearby cave and save Tellis from the satyrs.{^n}
tagRumorGr1DescA=ヘロスに羊飼いが 走ってきた。 牧草地から 群れを追って 家に帰る途中、 怪物に 襲われたのだ。 怪物どもは 彼の友人を 捕まえ、 道端の洞窟に 引きずり込んだ。 付近の洞窟を 見つけ出し、 サテュロスから テリスを救え。{^n}
//tagRumorGr1DescB=A shepherd came running up to Helos. Monsters had attacked him as he led his flock home from pasture. They grabbed his friend, Tellis, and dragged him into a cave by the roadside. Luckily, he was still alive, and you were able to save him.{^n}
tagRumorGr1DescB=ヘロスに羊飼いが 走ってきた。 牧草地から 群れを追って 家に帰る途中、 怪物に 襲われたのだ。 怪物どもは 彼の友人を 捕まえ、 道端の洞窟に 引きずり込んだ。 幸いにも 彼はまだ 生きており、 無事助け出す ことができた。{^n}
//tagRumorGr1DescC=It appears a group of the satyrs dragged a terrified shepherd into a cave by the roadside. Luckily, he was still alive, and you were able to save him. {^n}
tagRumorGr1DescC=一群のサテュロスが、 怯える羊飼いを 道端の洞窟に 引きずり込んだ。 幸いにも 彼はまだ 生きており、 無事助け出す ことができた。{^n}
//tagRumorGr1DescD=A shepherd came running up to Helos. Monsters had attacked him as led his flocks home from pasture. They grabbed his friend, Tellis, and dragged him into a cave by the roadside. The satyrs are dead. Speak to Tellis.{^n}
tagRumorGr1DescD=ヘロスに羊飼いが 走ってきた。 牧草地から 群れを追って 家に帰る途中、 怪物に 襲われたのだ。 怪物どもは 彼の友人を 捕まえ、 道端の洞窟に 引きずり込んだ。 サテュロスたちは 死んだ。 テリスに 話しかけよ。{^n}
//tagRumorGr1DescE=It appears a group of the satyrs dragged a terrified shepherd into a cave by the roadside. The satyrs are dead. Speak to the shepherd Tellis.{^n}
tagRumorGr1DescE=一群のサテュロスが、 怯える羊飼いを 道端の洞窟に 引きずり込んだ。 サテュロスたちは 死んだ。 羊飼いテリスに 話しかけよ。{^n}
//tagRumorGr1bDescA=Satyrs had surrounded a man after setting torch to his home in a small lumber camp. Fortunately you were able to defeat the satyrs.{^n}
tagRumorGr1bDescA=男がサテュロスに 囲まれている。 彼の家でもある 小さな製材所は 放火されて しまった。 サテュロスを 倒すことができて よかった。{^n}
//tagRumorGr2DescA=A traveler sitting by the roadside says he is stuck because satyrs, led by a champion, guard the narrow pass ahead. This man bears medicines for a strange illness in the village of Tegea, and many will die if the way is not cleared. Defeat the satyr brute blocking the pass and return to Euphadimus.{^n}
tagRumorGr2DescA=道端で座り込んでいた 旅人が言うには、 チャンピオンに 率いられた サテュロスどもが この先の 狭い小道を 封鎖しており、 おかげで 足止めされて いるとのこと。 テゲアの村で 発生した 奇病の薬を 運ぶ途中で、 彼がこの道を 通れなければ、 多くの命が 失われるだろう。 道を塞いでいる サテュロスを倒し、 エウパディモスの 所へ戻れ。{^n}
//tagRumorGr2DescB=Euphadimus, a traveler sitting by the roadside was stuck because satyrs, led by a champion, were guarding the narrow pass ahead. The man bore medicines for a strange illness in the village of Tegea. Hopefully he will reach the sick in time.{^n}
tagRumorGr2DescB=旅人エウパディモスは 道端に座り込み、 足止めを 食っていた。 チャンピオンに 率いられた サテュロスどもが、 この先の 狭い小道を 封鎖して いるためだ。 彼はテゲアの村で 発生した 奇病の薬を 運ぶ途中だった。 彼が一刻も早く 村に帰り 着くことを 祈ろう。{^n}
//tagRumorGr3DescA=A man lost the dowry for his daughter's wedding when beasts smashed his cart and ran off with his goods. The monsters have taken refuge in a nearby cave not far from the road. Find and return the dowry.{^n}
tagRumorGr3DescA=ある男が 娘の結婚祝いの 贈り物を 失くして しまった。 怪物どもが 荷馬車を叩き毀し、 荷物を持ち 去ったのだ。 怪物どもは 道からさほど 遠くない 洞窟を隠れ家と している。 嫁入り道具を 取り戻せ。{^n}
//tagRumorGr3DescB=A man lost the dowry for his daughter's wedding when beasts smashed his cart and ran off with his goods. The dowry was a fine gold necklace. Return the dowry to its owner, Theages.{^n}
tagRumorGr3DescB=ある男が 娘の結婚祝いの 贈り物を 失くして しまった。 怪物どもが 荷馬車を叩き毀し、 荷物を持ち 去ったのだ。 品物は純金の ネックレスだ。 持ち主の テアゲスへ 届けよ。{^n}
//tagRumorGr3DescC=A man lost the dowry for his daughter's wedding when beasts smashed his cart and ran off with his goods. With the necklace returned to him, wedding preparations can begin.{^n}
tagRumorGr3DescC=ある男が 娘の結婚祝いの 贈り物を 失くして しまった。 怪物どもが 荷馬車を叩き毀し、 荷物を持ち 去ったのだ。 ネックレスを 取り戻したので、 式の準備を 始められる。{^n}
//tagRumorGr4DescA=An old Spartan named Hippias wandered from the camp, and hasn't been seen. One of the soldiers is worried about him. Find Hippias and make sure he is unharmed.{^n}
tagRumorGr4DescA=ヒッピアスという スパルタの老人が、 野営地を 抜け出して 行方が分から なくなった。 兵士の一人が 心配している。 ヒッピアスを 捜し出し、 無事を確かめよ。{^n}
//tagRumorGr4DescC=An old Spartan named Hippias was resting in the Pellana valley. At first it seemed like he might be in danger, however it seems he was more of a threat to the monsters than they were to him!{^n}
tagRumorGr4DescC=ヒッピアスという スパルタの老人が、 ペラナ盆地で 休息を取っていた。 初めは彼が 危険に晒されて いるように 見えたが、 実は彼の 方が余程 怪物ども にとって 脅威だった らしい！{^n}
//tagRumorGr4DescB=An old Spartan named Hippias was resting in the Pellana valley. At first it seemed like he might be in danger, however it seems he was more of a threat to the monsters than they were to him! Bring the news to Euthycles in the Spartan camp.{^n}
tagRumorGr4DescB=ヒッピアスという スパルタの老人が、 ペラナ盆地で 休息を取っていた。 初めは彼が 危険に晒されて いるように 見えたが、 実は彼の 方が余程 怪物ども にとって 脅威だった らしい！ スパルタ軍 野営地の エウティクレスに 知らせよ。{^n}
//tagRumorGr5DescA=The local spring in Tegea recently turned foul and undrinkable. Search for the cause of the taint in the Tegea Woods.{^n}
tagRumorGr5DescA=最近テゲアの 泉が汚染され、 飲めなくなって しまった。 テゲアの森で 汚染の原因を 調査せよ。{^n}
//tagRumorGr5DescB=Recently, in Tegea, the local spring has been poisoned and turned foul. The spring belongs to the naiad Pegaea. She explained that spiders now taint the spring's source in a cave nearby. Destroy the spiders that dwell in the cave at the source of the spring.{^n}
tagRumorGr5DescB=最近テゲアの 泉が毒を含み、 汚染されて しまった。 この泉は 水の精 ペガイアの 住み処で、 近くの洞窟に 棲み着いた 蜘蛛が源泉を 汚していると 言うのだ。 蜘蛛を駆除せよ。{^n}
//tagRumorGr5DescC=Recently, in Tegea, the local spring has been poisoned and turned foul. The spiders that tainted the spring's source are dead. Speak to the naiad, Pegaea.{^n}
tagRumorGr5DescC=最近テゲアの 泉が毒を含み、 汚染されて しまった。 源泉を 汚していた 蜘蛛は 駆除された。 水の精 ペガイアに 話しかけよ。{^n}
//tagRumorGr5DescD=In Tegea, the local spring had turned foul and undrinkable. The spring, which belonged to the naiad Pegaea, had been tainted by giant spiders in a cave near its source. Now that they are gone, the spring will soon be drinkable again.{^n}
tagRumorGr5DescD=テゲアの泉が 汚染され、 飲めなくなって しまった。 水の精 ペガイアの 住み処でもある この泉は、 洞窟に巨大な 蜘蛛が棲み着き、 源泉を汚して いたのだ。 蜘蛛がいなく なったので、 泉の水は 間もなく 飲めるように なるだろう。{^n}
//tagRumorGr6DescA=People in Megara say they have been attacked by bands of skeletons and other creatures. Perhaps others in town have seen these undead and would know more.{^n}
tagRumorGr6DescA=メガラの人々の話では、 スケルトンを 初めとする 化け物の一団が 街を襲っている。 市中には、 目撃者や、 事情をもっと よく知って いる人が いるかも しれない。{^n}
//tagRumorGr6DescB=People in Megara say they have been attacked by bands of skeletons and other creatures. The undead seem to be coming from the ruins of an ancient city called Old Eleusis. Ask around to learn more of Old Eleusis.{^n}
tagRumorGr6DescB=メガラの人々の話では、 スケルトンを 初めとする 化け物の一団が 街を襲っている。 どうやら アンデッドは、 旧エレウシスなる 古代都市の 遺跡から 現れたらしい。 旧エレウシスに ついての 情報を集めよ。{^n}
//tagRumorGr6DescC=People in Megara say they have been attacked by bands of skeletons and other creatures. The undead seem to be coming from the ruins of an ancient city called Old Eleusis, where an old legend tells of three princes, whose remains haunt the place. Seek out the ancient ruins and destroy the three undead princes.{^n}
tagRumorGr6DescC=メガラの人々の話では、 スケルトンを 初めとする 化け物の一団が 街を襲っている。 どうやら アンデッドは、 旧エレウシスなる 古代都市の 遺跡から 現れたらしい。 その遺跡には、 今も取り憑いて いるという、 3人の王子に まつわる 古い伝説が あった。 遺跡を探索し、 アンデッドの 3王子を 滅ぼせ。{^n}
//tagRumorGr6DescD=People in Megara say they have been attacked by bands of skeletons and other creatures. Now that the three undead princes are gone, the undead should no longer wander from the ruins of an ancient city called Old Eleusis. Bring news of your victory to Autolycus in Megara.{^n}
tagRumorGr6DescD=メガラの人々の話では、 スケルトンを 初めとする 化け物の一団が 街を襲っている。 アンデッドの 3王子が 滅ぼされたので、 古代都市 旧エレウシスの 遺跡から アンデッドが さまよい 出ることは もうないだろう。 メガラの アウトリュコスに 勝利を伝えよ。{^n}
//tagRumorGr6DescE=People in Megara say they have been attacked by bands of skeletons and other creatures. Now that the three undead princes are gone, the undead should no longer wander from the ruins of an ancient city called Old Eleusis.{^n}
tagRumorGr6DescE=メガラの人々の話では、 スケルトンを 初めとする 化け物の一団が 街を襲っている。 アンデッドの 3王子が 滅ぼされたので、 古代都市 旧エレウシスの 遺跡から アンデッドが さまよい 出ることは もうないだろう。{^n}
//tagRumorGr7DescA=A trader was camping near a ruined city - only to be scared off by skeleton warriors! He told you his goods were free for the taking, if you could find them.{^n}
tagRumorGr7DescA=商人が廃墟の近くで 露営して いたところ、 スケルトン ウォーリアに 追い払われて しまった！ その商人は、 残してきた 商品は 見つけた者が 自由にして 構わない と言った。{^n}
//tagRumorGr7DescB=A trader was camping near a ruined city - only to be scared off by skeleton warriors! Although the camp was destroyed there were a few chests that remained untouched.{^n}
tagRumorGr7DescB=商人が廃墟の近くで 露営して いたところ、 スケルトン ウォーリアに 追い払われて しまった！ 露営地は 破壊されて いたが、 幾つかの チェストは 無傷で 残っていた。{^n}
//tagRumorGr8DescA=A sailor in Megara said his ship was wrecked by sirens. He washed ashore with the ship's wreckage on a beach along the Halcyon Coast. He said some of the ship's cargo washed up intact. Look for those chests among the wreckage.{^n}
tagRumorGr8DescA=メガラの水夫が、 セイレーンに 船を遭難 させられた。 彼は船の 残骸とともに ハルシオン 海岸の浜に 流され、 積み荷の 幾つかも 無傷で岸に 流れ着いた そうだ。 残骸の中から 積み荷の チェストを探せ。{^n}
//tagRumorGr8DescB=A sailor in Megara said his ship was wrecked by sirens. He washed ashore with the ship's wreckage on a beach along the Halcyon Coast. Some of the ship's cargo washed up intact, full of gold and equipment.{^n}
tagRumorGr8DescB=メガラの水夫が、 セイレーンに 船を遭難 させられた。 彼は船の 残骸とともに ハルシオン 海岸の浜に 流された。 積み荷も 幾つかは 無傷で、 中には 金貨と武具が 詰まっていた。{^n}
//tagRumorGr9DescA=A friendly centaur named Chiron stands in the woods, untroubled by the other beasts. He says he has a problem of some kind. Speak to him again to learn more.{^n}
tagRumorGr9DescA=森にケイロンという 友好的な ケンタウロスがいた。 森の動物とは うまくやっては いるのだが、 少々問題を 抱えている と言う。 もう一度 話しかけて 事情を聞け。{^n}
//tagRumorGr9DescB=A friendly centaur named Chiron stands in the woods. He claims a maenad named Ino grabbed his magic bow and ran into a nearby cave. Caves seem to unnerve Chiron, and he can't follow her. Retrieve the bow from Ino and return it to Chiron.{^n}
tagRumorGr9DescB=森にケイロンという 友好的な ケンタウロスがいた。 イノという メナードが、 彼の魔法の弓を ひったくって 近くの洞窟に 逃げ込んだ。 ケイロンは 洞窟に 怖気づいて 追うことが できずにいる。 イノから弓を 取り戻し、 ケイロンに 届けよ。{^n}
//tagRumorGr9DescC=A friendly centaur named Chiron stands in the woods, untroubled by the other beasts. A maenad named Ino grabbed his magic bow and ran into a nearby cave. The wise centaur was grateful to have his bow back, and is generous in this thanks.{^n}
tagRumorGr9DescC=森にケイロンという 友好的な ケンタウロスがいた。 森の動物とは うまくやって いたのだが、 イノという メナードが、 彼の魔法の弓を ひったくって 近くの洞窟に 逃げ込んだ。 この博識な ケンタウロスは 弓の返還に いたく喜び、 惜しみない 感謝を捧げた。 {^n}
//tagRumorGr10DescA=A villager said there is a master blacksmith, named Termerus, who lives alone off of the road to Delphi. He will sell his weapons and armor to any who find him.{^n}
tagRumorGr10DescA=村人によれば、 タルメロスという 鍛冶の達人が、 デルフォイへ 向かう道の 外れに 一人で住んで いるという。 彼は誰にでも 武器や防具を 売ってくれる。{^n}
//tagRumorGr10DescB=A villager said there is a master blacksmith, named Termerus, who lives alone off of the road to Delphi. His stock of weapons and armor are unmatched anywhere else in Greece.{^n}
tagRumorGr10DescB=村人によれば、 タルメロスという 鍛冶の達人が、 デルフォイへ 向かう道の 外れに 一人で住んで いるという。 その品物は、 他のギリシャの どんな街の 物とも 違っていた。{^n}
//tagRumorGr11DescA=A widow in Delphi lost her husband to a giant boar-man. In a dream her husband told her he could not cross into Hades to find rest among the dead while the boar-man lived. He told her the boar-man hides now in the Parnassus Caves. Find the boar-man and avenge her husband's death.{^n}
tagRumorGr11DescA=デルフォイで 巨大なボアマンによって 夫を失った 未亡人と 出会った。 その夫は 夢の中で 彼女に語った。 ボアマンが 生きている限り、 冥界へ渡り 安息を見出す ことはできぬ、 ボアマンは パルナッソスの 洞窟に隠れて いる、と。 ボアマンを 捜し出し、 仇をとれ。{^n}
//tagRumorGr11DescB=A widow in Delphi lost her husband to a giant boar-man. In a dream her husband told her he could not cross into Hades to find rest among the dead while the boar-man lived. Return to the widow Iodame with the news of the boar-man's defeat.{^n}
tagRumorGr11DescB=デルフォイで 巨大なボアマンによって 夫を失った 未亡人と 出会った。 その夫は 夢の中で 彼女に語った。 ボアマンが 生きている限り、 冥界へ渡り 安息を見出す ことはできぬ、 と。 未亡人 イオダメに ボアマンの 死を伝えよ。{^n}
//tagRumorGr11DescC=A widow in Delphi lost her husband to a giant boar-man. In a dream her husband told her he could not cross into Hades to find rest among the dead while the boar-man lived. Now that his death has been avenged, perhaps he has found his way to peaceful Elysium.{^n}
tagRumorGr11DescC=デルフォイで 巨大なボアマンによって 夫を失った 未亡人と 出会った。 その夫は 夢の中で 彼女に語った。 ボアマンが 生きている限り、 冥界へ渡り 安息を見出す ことはできぬ、 と。 復讐は 果たされた。 夫はおそらく 死後の楽園 エリュシオン への道を 辿っている だろう。{^n}
//tagRumorGr12DescA=A troop of Spartan soldiers have cornered a giant Limos in some ruins near Athens. They don't seem to have the nerve to take it on. Aid the soldiers by defeating the Limos.{^n}
tagRumorGr12DescA=スパルタ軍の一隊が アテネ付近の廃墟に 巨大なリモスを 追い詰めた ものの、 捕らえる までの度胸は なさそうだ。 助太刀して リモスを倒せ。{^n}
//tagRumorGr12DescB=A troop of Spartan soldiers had cornered a giant Limos in some ruins near Athens. They seemed relieved that somebody else was willing to fight it.{^n}
tagRumorGr12DescB=スパルタ軍の一隊が アテネ付近の廃墟に 巨大なリモスを 追い詰めた。 奴との戦いを 引き受ける 者が現れ、 ほっとして いるようだ。{^n}
//tagRumorGr12DescC=A troop of Spartan soldiers have cornered a giant Limos in some ruins, near Athens. Now that it is defeated, speak with Pausanias for your reward.{^n}
tagRumorGr12DescC=スパルタ軍の一隊が アテネ付近の廃墟に 巨大なリモスを 追い詰めた。 奴を倒したので、 パウサニアスと 報酬の話を しよう。{^n}
//tagRumorGr13DescA=A Spartan troop near Athens had sent a scouting party into a swamp nearby. They have yet to report back. Search for the missing soldiers in the swamp.{^n}
tagRumorGr13DescA=アテネ付近の スパルタ軍が 近くの沼地に 偵察隊を 送り込んだが、 それっきり 音沙汰がない。 沼地で 行方不明の 兵士たちを探せ。{^n}
//tagRumorGr13DescB=Several Spartan soldiers got lost while scouting a swamp on the road to Athens. Bring word that they're alive, and are on their way back, to their troop.{^n}
tagRumorGr13DescB=スパルタ軍の 一隊が、 アテネ付近の 沼地を探索中に 行方不明となった。 彼らの無事と、 まもなく 野営地に 帰還するで あろうことを、 本隊に報告せよ。{^n}
//tagRumorGr13DescC=A Spartan troop by some ruins had sent scouts into a nearby swamp. The scouts are fine, they just got lost, but their troop was worried With good directions, they will have no problem returning to their troop.{^n}
tagRumorGr13DescC=廃墟傍の スパルタ軍が 沼地に 偵察隊を 送った。 偵察隊は無事で、 道に迷った だけだった。 彼らが本隊に 合流するのは 難しいこと ではない だろう。{^n}
//tagRumorGr13DescD=Several Spartan soldiers got lost while scouting a swamp on the road to Athens. Their troop was glad to hear that they're alive and are on their way back.{^n}
tagRumorGr13DescD=スパルタ軍の 一隊が、 アテネ付近の 沼地を探索中に 行方不明となった。 彼らの生存と 帰還の報せに、 本隊の 兵士たちも 喜んだ。{^n}
//tagRumorGr0DescA=Timon said it is proper to bring an offering when seeking an audience with the Oracle of Delphi. He suggested an olive branch from the sacred tree in a grove near Ambrossos. Retrieve an olive branch and present it at the Temple of Apollo in Delphi.{^n}
tagRumorGr0DescA=ティモンが 言うには、 デルフォイの 巫女と接見 するためには 贈り物が 必要だ。 それは アンブロッソス 付近の 果樹園にある 聖なる樹の オリーブの 枝だと、 彼は教えて くれた。 オリーブの 枝を手に入れ、 デルフォイの アポロン神殿に 捧呈せよ。{^n}
//tagRumorGr0DescB=Timon said it is proper to bring an offering when seeking an audience with the Oracle of Delphi. The olive branch from the sacred tree pulses with a soothing, mystical heat. Present it at the Temple of Apollo in Delphi.{^n}
tagRumorGr0DescB=ティモンが 言うには、 デルフォイの 巫女と接見 するためには 贈り物が 必要だ。 聖なる樹の オリーブの枝は、 穏やかで 神秘的な熱を 帯びている。 デルフォイの アポロン神殿に 捧呈せよ。{^n}
//tagRumorGr0DescD=Timon said it is proper to bring an offering when seeking an audience with the Oracle of Delphi. He suggested an olive branch from the sacred tree in a grove near Ambrossos. Defeat the monster Arachne and take a branch from the sacred tree. Present it at the Temple of Apollo in Delphi.{^n}
tagRumorGr0DescD=ティモンが 言うには、 デルフォイの 巫女と接見 するためには 贈り物が 必要だ。 それは アンブロッソス 付近の 果樹園にある 聖なる樹の オリーブの 枝だと、 彼は教えて くれた。 アラクネを倒し、 聖なる樹から 枝を手に入れ、 デルフォイの アポロン神殿に 捧呈せよ。{^n}
//tagRumorGr0DescC=The Oracle's attendant took the offering gratefully. It is well, for the olive branch was hard won.{^n}
tagRumorGr0DescC=巫女の従者は 感謝して 進物を 受け取った。 オリーブの枝を 苦労して 手に入れた 甲斐があった。{^n}
//tagRumorGr15DescA=There are monsters loose in the market near the base of the Acropolis. How did they gain entrance to the city? Find the monsters and eliminate them.{^n}
tagRumorGr15DescA=アクロポリスの 麓にある市場を 怪物が 横行していた。 どうやって 街に侵入 したのだろう？ 怪物どもを 一掃せよ。{^n}
//tagRumorGr15DescB=There were monsters loose in the market near the base of the Acropolis. How did they gain entrance to the city? Hopefully no more creatures will breach the walls of Athens.{^n}
tagRumorGr15DescB=アクロポリスの 麓にある市場を 怪物が 横行していた。 どうやって 街に侵入 したのだろう？ 化け物が これ以上 アテネの 城壁を越えて 来なければ よいが。{^n}
//tagRumorGr16DescA=When the Telkine came to Knossos, a poisonous fog rolled in, and many of the villagers fell sick. Xanthippus, a healer, has been up on Tritons Ridge since the Telkine arrived. Nobody dares fetch him because of the monsters. Find Xanthippus and tell him of the sick villagers.{^n}
tagRumorGr16DescA=テルキンが クノッソスに やって来た際、 有毒の霧が 発生し、 多くの村人が 病を患った。 テルキンが 来て以来、 治療師 クサンティッポスは トリトン山中に 入ったままだ。 山中には 怪物がいて、 誰も彼を 連れ帰ることが できずにいる。 クサンティッポスを 見つけ出し、 村の病を 知らせよう。{^n}
//tagRumorGr16DescB=When the Telkine came to Knossos, a poisonous fog rolled in, and many of the villagers fell sick. Xanthippus cannot heal them without his staff which he dropped in a cave when monsters ambushed him. Retrieve the healer's staff from the cave.{^n}
tagRumorGr16DescB=テルキンが クノッソスに やって来た際、 有毒の霧が 発生し、 多くの村人が 病を患った。 クサンティッポスは 洞窟で怪物に 急襲され、 治療に必要な 杖を失って しまった。 洞窟へ行き、 治療師の杖を 取り戻せ。{^n}
//tagRumorGr16DescC=The healer Xanthippus dropped his healing staff in a cave when he was ambushed by monsters. Retrieve the healer's staff from the cave.{^n}
tagRumorGr16DescC=治療師 クサンティッポスは 洞窟で怪物に 急襲され、 杖をなくして しまった。 洞窟へ行き、 治療師の杖を 取り戻せ。{^n}
//tagRumorGr16DescD=When the Telkine came to Knossos, a poisonous fog rolled in, and many of the villagers fell sick. Now that Xanthippus has his healing staff, he can return to the village and tend to the people of Herakleion.{^n}
tagRumorGr16DescD=テルキンが クノッソスに やって来た際、 有毒の霧が 発生し、 多くの村人が 病を患った。 クサンティッポスは 杖を取り戻し、 村に戻って ヘラクレイオンの 人々を 治療する ことができた。{^n}
//tagRumorGr16DescE=Now that Xanthippus has his healing staff, he can once again tend to the sick.{^n}
tagRumorGr16DescE=クサンティッポスは 杖を取り戻し、 以前のように 病人を治療する ことができる ようになった。{^n}
//tagRumorGr17DescA=Old legends in Knossos tell of a wicked tyrant named Leucus who was poisoned by a servant. The legend claims the tyrant rose from his grave and walked the hills of Knossos. Search for him in a cave on Tritons Ridge.{^n}
tagRumorGr17DescA=クノッソスには、 召使に毒を 盛られた ルコスという 邪悪な暴君の 伝説がある。 その伝説の暴君が 墓から這い出し、 クノッソスの丘を 徘徊して いるという。 トリトン 山脈の 洞窟へ行き、 彼を捜し出せ。{^n}
//tagRumorGr17DescB=Old legends in Knossos tell of a wicked tyrant named Leucus who was poisoned by a servant. There was some truth to the legends, but he won't trouble the living any longer.{^n}
tagRumorGr17DescB=クノッソスには、 召使に毒を 盛られた ルコスという 邪悪な暴君の 伝説がある。 伝説は真実 だったのだ。 しかしもう 彼が人間を 煩わせる ことはない だろう。{^n}

//tagRumorEg1DescA=A noble warrior refuses to leave his post to search for a sword he lost in the slums, which was passed down in his family for generations. He puts his duty to protect the people of Rhakotis above all else. Find the ancestral sword and return it to the warrior Anherru.{^n}
tagRumorEg1DescA=気高き戦士が、 何代にも渡って 一族に受け 継がれて きた剣を スラム街で 失くして しまったが、 さりとて 彼は持ち場を 離れてまで 剣を探索 しようとは しなかった。 何よりも ラコティスの 人々を守る ことこそが 己の義務だと 考えているのだ。 家宝の剣を 捜し出し、 戦士アンヘルへ 届けよ。{^n}
//tagRumorEg1DescB=A noble warrior refused to leave his post to search for a sword he lost in the slums, which was passed down in his family for generations. Return the recovered weapon to the warrior Anherru.{^n}
tagRumorEg1DescB=気高き戦士が、 何代にも渡って 一族に受け 継がれて きた剣を スラム街で 失くして しまったが、 さりとて 彼は持ち場を 離れてまで 剣を探索 しようとは しなかった。 戦士アンヘルのために 剣を取り戻せ。{^n}
//tagRumorEg1DescC=Anherru refused to go back for a sword he lost, which was passed down in his family for generations. He puts his duty to protect the people of Rhakotis above all else. Still, he seemed glad to have it back. It must have meant a lot to him.{^n}
tagRumorEg1DescC=アンヘルは 何代にも渡って 一族に受け 継がれて きた剣を 失くして しまったが、 それを探しに 引き返そうとは しなかった。 何よりも ラコティスの 人々を守る ことこそが 己の義務だと 考えているのだ。 しかし剣を 取り戻せて 嬉しそうだ。 とても大切な ものだったに 違いない。{^n}
//tagRumorEg2DescA=A local legend tells of a great Ancient Scorpos that lives in a cave in Wadjet Canyon, preying on travelers. It is said that whoever kills the Scorpos will receive a magical blessing.{^n}
tagRumorEg2DescA=土地の伝説によれば、 ワジェト 峡谷の洞窟に 旅人を食らう 巨大な古代の サソリが 棲むという。 そのサソリを 退治した 者には、 魔法の祝福が あると伝え られている。{^n}
//tagRumorEg2DescB=A local legend told of a great Ancient Scorpos in Wadjet Canyon, preying on travelers. Now it will be no more than a tale. The beast is dead.{^n}
tagRumorEg2DescB=土地の伝説によれば、 ワジェト 峡谷の洞窟に 旅人を食らう 巨大な古代の サソリが 棲むという。 作り話では なかった。 そいつは死んだ。{^n}
//tagRumorEg3DescA=Near the Temple of Ptah, a sorceress of the Order of Prometheus was surrounded and outnumbered. She was grateful for the help in defeating the monsters.{^n}
tagRumorEg3DescA=プタハ神殿の近くで、 プロメテウス 騎士団の 魔術師が 包囲されていた。 彼女は 助太刀に いたく感謝した。{^n}
//tagRumorEg4DescA=The farmers in Egypt have a hard lot. These poor farmers are suffering under nightly raids by a strange breed of monster: part man, part reptile. Find and eliminate these reptilians.{^n}
tagRumorEg4DescA=エジプトの農民が 困窮している。 この哀れな 農民たちは、 半人半爬虫類の 奇妙な怪物に 夜ごと襲撃されて 苦しんでいる。 爬虫類人を 殲滅せよ。{^n}
//tagRumorEg4DescB=The farmers in Egypt have a hard lot. These poor farmers are suffering under nightly raids by some half breed of creatures; part man, part reptile. It took some work to find these reptilian raiders, but they won't be troubling the farmers any longer.{^n}
tagRumorEg4DescB=エジプトの農民が 困窮している。 この哀れな 農民たちは、 半人半爬虫類の 奇妙な怪物に 夜ごと襲撃されて 苦しんでいる。 爬虫類人の 侵略者を 見つけるのには 手間取ったが、 もう奴らが 農民たちを 悩ませる ことはない だろう。{^n}
tagRumorEg5DescA=ボロを纏った 貫禄ある男が、 乞食の群集の 前に立ち、 城壁外の 無防備な 家々を 守るため、 怪物どもを 退治して くれるよう 嘆願した。 貧民街から 怪物どもを 一掃し、 安全を 確保せよ。{^n}
//tagRumorEg5DescB=A dignified man in rags stood before a crowd of poor beggars. He pleaded for help clearing monsters from their flimsy, unprotected homes outside the city walls. Return to Merab and let him know his home is safe once more.{^n}
tagRumorEg5DescB=ボロを纏った 貫禄ある男が、 乞食の群集の 前に立ち、 城壁外の 無防備な 家々を 守るため、 怪物どもを 退治して くれるよう 嘆願した。 メラブの 元に戻り、 危険が 去ったことを 知らせよ。{^n}
//tagRumorEg5DescC=A dignified man in rags stood before a crowd of poor beggars. He pleaded for help clearing monsters from their flimsy, unprotected homes outside the city walls. His gift of thanks was… unexpected. Who was that man?{^n}
tagRumorEg5DescC=ボロを纏った 貫禄ある男が、 乞食の群集の 前に立ち、 城壁外の 無防備な 家々を 守るため、 怪物どもを 退治して くれるよう 嘆願した。 そのお礼の品は 予想外の 代物だった。 一体何者だろう？{^n}
//tagRumorEg6DescA=The High Priest of Memphis seems to want your help. Speak to him again to learn more.{^n}
tagRumorEg6DescA=メンフィスの高僧が 助けを求めて いるようだ。 もう一度 話しかけて 詳細を尋ねよ。{^n}
//tagRumorEg6DescB=The High Priest of Memphis seems to want your help. Speak to him again, and hopefully he will get to the point.{^n}
tagRumorEg6DescB=メンフィスの高僧が 助けを求めて いるようだ。 もう一度 話しかけよう。 はっきりと 要点を教えて くれれば よいが。{^n}
//tagRumorEg6DescC=The High Priest of Memphis says he needs the staff of Khufu, from the pyramid in Giza, in order to restore his authority and prevent panic and chaos in Memphis. Retrieve the staff from the Pharaoh's sarcophagus beneath the pyramid and bring it to the High Priest Zazamankh.{^n}
tagRumorEg6DescC=メンフィスの高僧が、 彼の権威を 回復し、 メンフィスの 混乱と無秩序を 防ぐため、 ギゼの ピラミッドにある クフ王の杖を 必要としている。 ピラミッド 深奥部の ファラオの 石棺から 杖を取り戻し、 高僧ザザマンクに 届けよ。{^n}
//tagRumorEg6DescD=The High Priest of Memphis says he needs the staff of Khufu, from the pyramid in Giza, in order to restore his authority and prevent panic and chaos in Memphis. Bring the staff to the High Priest Zazamankh.{^n}
tagRumorEg6DescD=メンフィスの高僧が、 彼の権威を 回復し、 メンフィスの 混乱と無秩序を 防ぐため、 ギゼの ピラミッドにある クフ王の杖を 必要としている。 杖を高僧 ザザマンクに 届けよ。{^n}
//tagRumorEg6DescE=Now that he has the Staff of Khufu, the High Priest of Memphis will use his authority for the good of the people, with wisdom and strength in these hard times.{^n}
tagRumorEg6DescE=クフ王の杖を 取り戻した メンフィスの 高僧は、 民のために 知恵と力を 振り絞り、 この困難な時代に 立ち向かう だろう。{^n}
//tagRumorEg7DescA=A woman in Memphis is worried – her brother is missing. Speak with her again to learn more.{^n}
tagRumorEg7DescA=メンフィスで 女性が困っている。 弟が行方 不明なのだ。 もう一度 話しかけ、 詳細を尋ねよ。{^n}
//tagRumorEg7DescB=A woman in Memphis is worried – her brother Unas is missing. She fears he has gone to Giza, with the hopes of awaking an ancient family guardian for the purpose of fighting the monsters. Search for him in the family's tomb there.{^n}
tagRumorEg7DescB=メンフィスで 女性が困っている。 弟ウナスが 行方不明 なのだ。 彼女は弟が ギゼへ行ったの ではないかと 心配している。 先祖一族の ガーディアンを 呼び起こし、 怪物どもと 戦わせようと しているの ではないかと。 一族の 墓所へ行き、 彼を探せ。{^n}
//tagRumorEg7DescC=A woman in Memphis was worried – she feared her brother Unas has gone to Giza, with the hopes of awaking an ancient family guardian for the purpose of fighting the monsters. You found him terrified, standing on the threshold of the hereditary vault. Enter the vault and find out what the problem is.{^n}
tagRumorEg7DescC=メンフィスで 女性が困っている。 弟ウナスが 行方不明 なのだ。 彼女は弟が ギゼへ行ったの ではないかと 心配している。 先祖一族の ガーディアンを 呼び起こし、 怪物どもと 戦わせようと しているの ではないかと。 先祖代々の 墓所の前で 恐怖に震える ウナスを 見つけた。 墓所に入り、 異常がないか 確かめよ。{^n}
//tagRumorEg7DescD=A woman in Memphis was worried – she fears her brother Unas has gone to Giza, with the hopes of awaking an ancient family guardian for the purpose of fighting the monsters. You found Unas, terrified, before his hereditary vault. He had awakened the guardian, which was sworn to serve his family – but it fell under the madness of the Telkine. Speak to Unas again, and return to Tathari with the news.{^n}
tagRumorEg7DescD=メンフィスで 女性が困っている。 弟ウナスが 行方不明 なのだ。 彼女は弟が ギゼへ行ったの ではないかと 心配している。 先祖一族の ガーディアンを 呼び起こし、 怪物どもと 戦わせようと しているの ではないかと。 先祖代々の 墓所の前で 恐怖に震える ウナスを 見つけた。 ガーディアンを 呼び起こしは したものの、 一族に仕えると 誓った ガーディアンは、 テルキンの 魔力に操られて しまっていた。 再度ウナスに 話しかけ、 タタリに 報告に戻れ。{^n}
//tagRumorEg7DescE=Unas left Memphis without warning his sister, and made the dangerous trek to Giza with the hopes of awaking an ancient family guardian for the purpose of fighting the monsters. You found Unas terrified before his hereditary vault. He had awakened the guardian, which was sworn to serve his family – until it fell under the spell of madness cast by the Telkine.{^n}
tagRumorEg7DescE=姉に無断で メンフィスを 発ったウナスは、 ギゼまで 危険な旅をし、 一族の ガーディアンを 呼び起こして 怪物どもと 戦わせようと したのだった。 先祖代々の 墓所の前で 恐怖に震える ウナスを 見つけた。 ガーディアンを 呼び起こしは したものの、 一族に仕えると 誓ったはずの ガーディアンは、 テルキンの 魔力に操られて しまっていた。{^n}
//tagRumorEg7DescF=A man named Unas stands terrified before the threshold of his hereditary vault in Giza. Go into the vault to find out what the problem is.{^n}
tagRumorEg7DescF=ギゼにある 先祖代々の 墓所の前で 恐怖に震える ウナスを 見つけた。 墓所に入り、 異常がないか 確かめよ。{^n}
//tagRumorEg7DescG=A man named Unas stood terrified before the threshold of his hereditary vault in Giza. The guardian inside is now dead. Speak to Unas.{^n}
tagRumorEg7DescG=ギゼにある 先祖代々の 墓所の前で 恐怖に震える ウナスを 見つけた。 墓所内の ガーディアンは 死んだ。 ウナスに 話かけよ。{^n}
//tagRumorEg7DescH=Unas left Memphis without warning his sister, and made the dangerous trek to Giza with the hopes of awaking an ancient family guardian for the purpose of fighting the monsters. You found Unas terrified before his hereditary vault. He had awakened the guardian, which was sworn to serve his family – until it fell under the spell of madness cast by the Telkine. Bring his sister Tathari news in Memphis.{^n}
tagRumorEg7DescH=姉に無断で メンフィスを 発ったウナスは、 ギゼまで 危険な旅をし、 一族の ガーディアンを 呼び起こして 怪物どもと 戦わせようと したのだった。 先祖代々の 墓所の前で 恐怖に震える ウナスを 見つけた。 ガーディアンを 呼び起こしは したものの、 一族に仕えると 誓ったはずの ガーディアンは、 テルキンの 魔力に操られて しまっていた。 メンフィスに戻り、 姉のタタリに 報告せよ。{^n}
//tagRumorEg8DescA=A frantic man said that monsters have broken into the great pyramid. He said that if they defile the Pharaoh's sarcophagus, it will unleash a deadly plague on the land.{^n}
tagRumorEg8DescA=取り乱した 遊牧民が、 怪物が 大ピラミッドに 侵入した と言った。 もし奴らが ファラオの 石棺を 冒涜する ようなことに なれば、 死の病が 地上にはびこる ことになると 言う。{^n}
//tagRumorEg8DescB=A frantic nomad said that monsters have broken into the great pyramid. If they had defiled the Pharaoh's sarcophagus, it would have unleashed a deadly plague on the land. The monsters have been defeated. Return to the nomad Tekenu.{^n}
tagRumorEg8DescB=取り乱した 遊牧民が、 怪物が 大ピラミッドに 侵入した と言った。 もし奴らが ファラオの 石棺を 冒涜する ようなことに なれば、 死の病が 地上にはびこる ことになると 言うのだ。 怪物どもは 退治した。 遊牧民テケヌの 元に戻れ。{^n}
//tagRumorEg8DescC=A frantic nomad said that monsters have broken into the great pyramid. If they had defiled the Pharaoh's sarcophagus, it would have unleashed a deadly plague on the land. Thankfully, the monsters were not able to defile the sarcophagus.{^n}
tagRumorEg8DescC=取り乱した 遊牧民が、 怪物が 大ピラミッドに 侵入した と言った。 もし奴らが ファラオの 石棺を 冒涜する ようなことに なれば、 死の病が 地上にはびこる ことになると 言うのだ。 幸いにも、 怪物どもは 石棺を 穢すことは できなかった。{^n}
//tagRumorEg9DescA=A rather disreputable figure in the market bazaar mentioned some kind of tomb he found, filled with treasure – and monsters. Search for the tomb and claim the forgotten treasure.{^n}
tagRumorEg9DescA=市場にいた やや胡散臭い 人物によれば、 宝と怪物で 溢れた墓地を 見つけたという。 墓地を 探し出し、 忘れ去られた 宝物を 入手せよ。{^n}
//tagRumorEg9DescB=You have discovered an ancient unmarked tomb. The monsters could not prevent you from discovering a great cache of treasure.{^n}
tagRumorEg9DescB=墓標のない 太古の墓を 見つけた。 怪物どもに 邪魔はされたが、 隠し宝物庫を 発見した。{^n}
//tagRumorEg10DescA=There is a man in the market here whose caravan was ambushed. He managed to escape, but the raiders took all his goods. Ask around Fayum to learn more.{^n}
tagRumorEg10DescA=市場にいた男の キャラバンが 奇襲されたという。 彼はなんとか 逃げおおせたが、 荷物は全て 略奪されて しまった。 ファイユームで 情報を集めよ。{^n}
//tagRumorEg10DescB=It appears that a single dune raider tribe, led by their chieftain, Iznu, has attacked so many caravans that no more are coming. Find and defeat Iznu.{^n}
tagRumorEg10DescB=首領イズヌーに 率いられた デューン レイダーの 一部族に 多くの キャラバンが 襲われ、 おかげで 往来が滞って いるようだ。 イズヌーを 探し出し、 倒せ。{^n}
//tagRumorEg10DescC=It appears that a single dune raider tribe, led by their chieftain, Iznu, has attacked so many caravans that no more are coming. In fact, there is a man in the market in Fayum whose caravan was just ambushed. He got away, but the raiders took all the goods. Find and defeat Iznu.{^n}
tagRumorEg10DescC=首領イズヌーに 率いられた デューン レイダーの 一部族に 多くの キャラバンが 襲われ、 おかげで 往来が滞って いるようだ。 事実、 ファイユームの 市場には、 つい先だって 襲われた ばかりの キャラバン 商人がいる。 彼自身は なんとか 逃げおおせたが、 荷物は全て 略奪された。 イズヌーを 探し出し、 倒せ。{^n}
//tagRumorEg10DescD=It appears that a single dune raider tribe, led by their chieftain, Iznu, had attacked so many caravans that no more are coming. Now that he and his tribe are gone, perhaps the oasis town can once more receive much-needed supplies. Return and speak to Fayum villager Pa-neb.{^n}
tagRumorEg10DescD=首領イズヌーに 率いられた デューン レイダーの 一部族に 多くの キャラバンが 襲われ、 おかげで 往来が滞って いるようだ。 イズヌーと その部族を 倒したので、 オアシスは 再び日用品を 確保できる ようになる だろう。 ファイユームへ戻り、 村人パネブと 話そう。{^n}
//tagRumorEg10DescE=It appears that a single dune raider tribe, led by their chieftain, Iznu, had attacked so many caravans that no more are coming. Now that he and his tribe are gone, perhaps the oasis town can once more receive much-needed supplies.{^n}
tagRumorEg10DescE=首領イズヌーに 率いられた デューン レイダーの 一部族に 多くの キャラバンが 襲われ、 おかげで 往来が滞って いるようだ。 イズヌーと その部族を 倒したので、 オアシスは 再び日用品を 確保できる ようになる だろう。{^n}
//tagRumorEg11DescA=One brave priest stood against the Telkine, as it passed through the Temple of Seti. Unfortunately, the priest was defeated and transformed into some kind of monster. Search for the corrupted priest somewhere near the Valley of the Kings.{^n}
tagRumorEg11DescA=テルキンが セティ寺院を 通り過ぎた時、 1人の勇敢な 僧侶が彼奴に 立ち向かった。 残念ながら 僧侶は敗れ、 何らかの 化け物に 姿を変えられて しまった。 王家の谷 付近で 堕ちた僧侶を 探しだせ。{^n}
//tagRumorEg11DescB=One brave priest stood against the Telkine as it passed through the Temple of Seti. Unfortunately, the priest was defeated and transformed into some kind of monster. The poor priest was neither alive nor human, anymore... At least, now, he will rest peacefully. Tell the priest Amen-nahte what has happened.{^n}
tagRumorEg11DescB=テルキンが セティ寺院を 通り過ぎた時、 1人の勇敢な 僧侶が彼奴に 立ち向かった。 残念ながら 僧侶は敗れ、 何らかの 化け物に 姿を変えられて しまった。 僧侶アメン ナハテに 何が起こったかを 伝えよ。{^n}
//tagRumorEg11DescC=The brave priest that tried to defend the Temple of Seti from the Telkine was transformed into a terrible monster. You have laid this creature to rest.{^n}
tagRumorEg11DescC=セティ寺院を テルキンから 守ろうとした 勇敢な僧侶は、 恐ろしい 化け物に 姿を変えられて しまっていた。 哀れな彼を 埋葬した。{^n}

//tagRumorOR0DescA=One of the Shangshung said he went into some ice caverns on the far side of a nearby valley. He said he saw a gargantuan yeti there, which he had confused with some old myths of a giant that sleeps beneath a mountain. Search for the yeti in those caves.{^n}
tagRumorOR0DescA=とあるシャンシュン人が、 付近の谷の 向こう側の 氷の洞窟に 入ったそうだ。 そこで彼は 巨大な イエティを 目撃したが、 古い伝説の 巨人と 見まがう程 だったという。 洞窟へ行きイエティを探せ。{^n}
//tagRumorOR0DescB=One of the Shangshung said he went into some ice caverns on the far side of a nearby valley. He said he saw a gargantuan yeti there, which he had confused with some old myths of a giant that sleeps beneath a mountain. The cries of the yeti will no longer echo through the valley.{^n}
tagRumorOR0DescB=とあるシャンシュン人が、 付近の谷の 向こう側の 氷の洞窟に 入ったそうだ。 そこで彼は 巨大な イエティを 目撃したが、 古い伝説の 巨人と 見まがう程 だったという。 イエティの 雄叫びが 谷にこだまする ことはもう ないだろう。{^n}
//tagRumorOR0DescC=A giant yeti dwelled in the ice caverns in Chumbi valley. Travelers feared to pass through the caverns. The great beast's cries will no longer echo through these icy walls.{^n}
tagRumorOR0DescC=チュンビ谷の 氷の洞窟に 巨大なイエティが 住んでいた。 旅人は洞窟を 通り抜けるのを 恐れた。 巨大な野獣の 雄叫びが 氷壁を超えて こだまする ことはもう ないだろう。{^n}
//tagRumorOr1DescA=In the wake of the Telkine's flight from Babylon, monsters have swarmed over the rolling farmland. One farmer who had not fled watched the monsters make splinters and wreckage of all he owned. Save his farm from the monsters.{^n}
tagRumorOr1DescA=バビロンから テルキンが 飛来した直後、 緩やかに 起伏した 農地に、 怪物の大群が 押し寄せてきた。 ある農夫は 逃げ出さず、 怪物どもが 彼の全財産を 粉々に 破壊するのを 目撃した。 怪物どもから 農場を救え。{^n}
//tagRumorOr1DescB=In the wake of the Telkine's flight from Babylon, monsters have swarmed over the rolling farmland. One farmer who had not fled watched the monsters make splinters and wreckage of all he owned. Return to the farmer Immeru.{^n}
tagRumorOr1DescB=バビロンから テルキンが 飛来した直後、 緩やかに 起伏した 農地に、 怪物の大群が 押し寄せてきた。 ある農夫は 逃げ出さず、 怪物どもが 彼の全財産を 粉々に 破壊するのを 目撃した。 農夫インメルの 元に戻れ。{^n}
//tagRumorOr1DescC=In the wake of the Telkine's flight from Babylon, monsters have swarmed over the rolling farmland. One farmer who had not fled watched the monsters make splinters and wreckage of all he owned. He was grateful to see them dealt with, but most likely his troubles are not ended.{^n}
tagRumorOr1DescC=バビロンから テルキンが 飛来した直後、 緩やかに 起伏した 農地に、 怪物の大群が 押し寄せてきた。 ある農夫は 逃げ出さず、 怪物どもが 彼の全財産を 粉々に 破壊するのを 目撃した。 怪物どもが 退治された のを見て、 彼は喜んだ。 しかし 彼の苦労は 終わっては いなさそうだ。{^n}
//tagRumorOr3DescA=A trader was trapped by monsters in a mountain pass. After it was safe, he talked about the hardships of trading on the Silk Road.{^n}
tagRumorOr3DescA=山道で商人が 怪物の罠に 嵌っていた。 救い出されたのち、 彼はシルク ロードで 商売する 苦労について 語った。{^n}
//tagRumorOr4DescA=A Shangshung villager is troubled. He says that nearby neanderthal tribes have suddenly grown hostile and brazen. Many humans have been attacked. Meanwhile, his son has been missing for several days, and he fears the worst. Speak to other Shangshung villagers, and look for the man's son.{^n}
tagRumorOr4DescA=シャンシュンの 村人が困っている。 近くに棲む ネアンデルタール族が 突然厚かましく、 敵対的に なったという。 多くの人間が 襲われた。 この非常時に、 彼の息子が 数日来 行方不明で、 最悪の事態を 恐れている。 シャンシュンの 他の村人にも 話を聞き、 彼の息子を 探せ。{^n}
//tagRumorOr4DescB=A Shangshung villager spoke of nearby neanderthal tribes growing suddenly hostile and brazen. His son has been missing for several days, and he fears the worst. Meanwhile, evil spirits have taken up residence in the burial cave by the Shangshung temple. Defeat the evil spirits.{^n}
tagRumorOr4DescB=シャンシュンの 村人によれば、 近くに棲む ネアンデルタール族が 突然厚かましく、 敵対的に なったという。 また、 彼の息子が ここ数日 行方不明で、 最悪の事態を 恐れている。 一方、 シャンシュンの 寺院の傍の 葬窟に 邪悪な幽霊が 棲み憑いた。 邪霊を 退治せよ。{^n}
//tagRumorOr4DescC=A Shangshung villager spoke of nearby neanderthal tribes growing suddenly hostile and brazen. His son has been missing for several days, and he fears the worst. Meanwhile, the burial cave by the Shangshung temple was plagued with evil spirits. Speak to the villager Ang Tshe-ring and tell him you have cleansed the cave.{^n}
tagRumorOr4DescC=シャンシュンの 村人によれば、 近くに棲む ネアンデルタール族が 突然厚かましく、 敵対的に なったという。 また、 彼の息子が ここ数日 行方不明で、 最悪の事態を 恐れている。 一方、 シャンシュンの 寺院の傍の 葬窟に 邪悪な幽霊が 棲み憑いた。 村人アン ツェリンに 葬窟が浄化 されたことを 伝えよ。{^n}
//tagRumorOr4DescD=A Shangshung villager spoke of nearby neanderthal tribes growing suddenly hostile and brazen. His son has been missing for several days, and he fears the worst. Meanwhile, the burial cave by the Shangshung temple was plagued with evil spirits… and the sacred ancestral weapons kept there have been stolen! Search for the weapons and the lost son.{^n}
tagRumorOr4DescD=シャンシュンの 村人によれば、 近くに棲む ネアンデルタール族が 突然厚かましく、 敵対的に なったという。 また、 彼の息子が ここ数日 行方不明で、 最悪の事態を 恐れている。 一方、 シャンシュンの 寺院の傍の 葬窟に 邪悪な幽霊が 棲み憑き、 さらに そこに保管 されていた 先祖伝来の 聖なる武器が 盗まれて しまった。 武器と 行方不明の 息子を探せ。{^n}
//tagRumorOr4DescL=The fog of mystery begins to clear. When the Telkine's influence made the neanderthals mad, the Shangshung villager's son took the ancestral weapons from their place in the burial cave. He hoped to make these mountains safe forever. Sadly, he was not the hero he hoped to be, and neanderthals ambushed him, taking the sacred weapons. Now his people are less safe than before. Find and defeat the Neanderthals who took the sacred weapons.{^n}
tagRumorOr4DescL=謎が解け始めた。 テルキンの影響で ネアンデルタール族が 正気を失い、 シャンシュンの 村人の息子が 先祖伝来の 武器を葬窟から 持ち出したのだ。 不幸にも、 彼は自分が 望んだような 英雄には なれなかった。 ネアンデルタール族に 襲われ、 聖なる武器を 奪われたのだ。 今や村人は さらなる 危険に晒され ている。 聖なる 武器を奪った ネアンデルタール族を 探し出し、 倒せ。{^n}
//tagRumorOr4DescE=When the Telkine's influence made the neanderthals mad, a Shangshung villager's son took the ancestral weapons from their place in the burial cave, hoping to make these mountains safe. His plan failed when neanderthals ambushed him, taking the sacred weapons. The neanderthals were defeated and the weapons recovered. Speak to Kilu Tem-ba in the Shangshung Village. {^n}
tagRumorOr4DescE=テルキンの影響で ネアンデルタール族が 正気を失い、 シャンシュンの 村人の息子が 先祖伝来の 武器を葬窟から 持ち出し、 山の安全を 取り戻そうとした。 だがネアンデルタール族の 奇襲で 聖なる武器を 強奪され、 計画は頓挫した。 ネアンデルタール族は 敗れ去り、 武器は取り 戻された。シャンシュン村の キリュ テムバに 話しかけよう。{^n}
//tagRumorOr4DescF=When the Telkine's influence made the neanderthals mad, a Shangshung villager's son took the ancestral weapons from their place in the burial cave, hoping to make these mountains safe. His plan failed when neanderthals ambushed him, taking the sacred weapons. Now that the greatest danger has passed, do the Shangshung really want weapons they cannot master?{^n}
tagRumorOr4DescF=テルキンの影響で ネアンデルタール族が 正気を失い、 シャンシュンの 村人の息子が 先祖伝来の 武器を葬窟から 持ち出し、 山の安全を 取り戻そうとした。 だがネアンデルタール族の 奇襲で 聖なる武器を 強奪され、 計画は頓挫した。 今や最大の 危機は去った。 シャンシュンの 人々は、 扱えもしない 武器を本当に 欲しいの だろうか？{^n}
//tagRumorOr4DescG=It appears that evil spirits have taken up in the burial cave by the Shangshung temple. Defeat the evil spirits.{^n}
tagRumorOr4DescG=シャンシュン村の 傍の葬窟に、 邪悪な幽霊が 住み着いた ようだ。 邪霊を倒せ。{^n}
//tagRumorOr4DescH=The burial cave by the Shangshung temple was plagued with evil spirits… and the sacred ancestral weapons kept there have been stolen! Search for the stolen weapons.{^n}
tagRumorOr4DescH=シャンシュン村の 葬窟には 邪霊が はびこっていた。 さらに、 そこに保管 されていた 先祖伝来の 聖なる武器が 盗まれていた！ 盗まれた 武器を探せ。{^n}
//tagRumorOr4DescI=A young man stood in the wilderness, shaken and dejected. It seems he took the sacred ancestral weapons from their place in the Shangshung temple burial cave. He hoped to make these mountains safe forever. Sadly, he was not the hero he hoped to be, and neanderthals ambushed him, taking the sacred weapons. Find and defeat the Neanderthals who took the sacred weapons.{^n}
tagRumorOr4DescI=しょんぼりした 若者が荒野に 立っていた。 シャンシュンの 葬窟から 聖なる武器を 持ち出したのは 彼らしい。 不幸にも、 彼は自分が 望んだような 英雄には なれなかった。 ネアンデルタール族に 襲われ、 聖なる武器を 奪われたのだ。 武器を奪った ネアンデルタール族を 探し出し、 倒せ。{^n}
//tagRumorOr4DescJ=A young man stood in the wilderness, shaken and dejected. It seems he took the sacred ancestral weapons from their place in the Shangshung temple burial cave. He hoped to make these mountains safe forever. Sadly, he was not the hero he hoped to be, and neanderthals ambushed him, taking the sacred weapons. With the ancestral weapons out of neanderthal hands, the greatest danger is gone. Do the Shangshung really want weapons they cannot master? Speak to the distraught young man.{^n}
tagRumorOr4DescJ=しょんぼりした 若者が荒野に 立っていた。 シャンシュンの 葬窟から 聖なる武器を 持ち出したのは 彼らしい。 不幸にも、 彼は自分が 望んだような 英雄には なれなかった。 ネアンデルタール族に 襲われ、 聖なる武器を 奪われたのだ。 ネアンデルタール族の 手から 聖なる武器を 取り返し、 最大の危機は 去った。 シャンシュンの 人々は、 扱えもしない 武器を本当に 欲しいの だろうか？ 落ち込んで いる若者に 話しかけよ。{^n}
//tagRumorOr4DescK=A young man stood in the wilderness, shaken and dejected. It seems he took the ancestral weapons from their place in the burial cave, hoping to make these mountains safe. His plan failed when neanderthals ambushed him, taking the sacred weapons. The neanderthals were defeated and the weapons recovered. Find and speak to his father, Kilu Tem-ba, in the Shangshung Village.{^n}
tagRumorOr4DescK=しょんぼりした 若者が荒野に 立っていた。 彼はシャンシュンの 葬窟から 聖なる武器を 持ち出し、 山の安全を 取り戻そうと したのだ。 だがネアンデルタール族の 奇襲で 聖なる武器を 強奪され、 計画は頓挫した。 ネアンデルタール族は 敗れ去り、 武器は取り 戻された。 シャンシュン村にいる 彼の父親 キリュ テムバに 話かけよ。{^n}
//tagRumorOr5DescA=A trader was trapped by monsters in a mountain pass. After it was safe, he talked about the difficulties of trading.{^n}
tagRumorOr5DescA=山道で商人が 怪物の罠に 嵌っていた。 救い出されたのち、 彼は商売の 難しさに ついて語った。{^n}
//tagRumorOr6DescA=A proud warrior was standing in the woods, fighting bravely but completely without hope. He seemed to want to die. Speak with him to learn more.{^n}
tagRumorOr6DescA=森の中に 堂々たる 戦士がいた。 勇敢に 戦っては いたが、 将来に希望が もてず、 死を望んで いるよう だった。 彼の話を 聞いてみよう。{^n}
//tagRumorOr6DescB=A proud warrior was standing in the woods, fighting bravely but completely without hope. He seemed to want to die. After talking with him, he seemed to take heart and overcome his despair. He began to see that the warrior is bound by duty to protect the defenseless. By saving the innocent, the warrior makes hope where there was none.{^n}
tagRumorOr6DescB=森の中に 堂々たる 戦士がいた。 勇敢に 戦っては いたが、 将来に希望が もてず、 死を望んで いるよう だった。 話しかけると、 彼は気を 取り直し、 絶望を 克服した ようだ。 戦士は 義務として 弱き者を 守らねば ならないと 思い始めた のだろう。 罪なき人々を 救うことで、 戦士は 絶望の中に 希望を 見出すのだ。{^n}
//tagRumorOr7DescA=A terrified woman near a burned out village watched a raptor wander between her and her playing child. There was nothing she could do. Slay the beast before it notices the child.{^n}
tagRumorOr7DescA=村の焼け跡で 震えていた女性が、 近くで 遊んでいた 我が子のそばへ ラプターが 迷い込んで きたのに 気づいたが、 彼女は何も できないでいた。 野獣が 子どもに気づく 前に倒せ。{^n}
//tagRumorOr7DescB=A terrified woman near a burned out village watched a raptor wander between her and her playing child. There was nothing she could do. No words could describe the joy of the mother and child, safely together again.{^n}
tagRumorOr7DescB=村の焼け跡で 震えていた女性が、 近くで 遊んでいた 我が子のそばへ ラプターが 迷い込んで きたのに 気づいたが、 彼女は何も できないでいた。 母と子が 無事再会を 果たした 喜びを表現する 言葉などない。{^n}
//tagRumorOr8DescA=A group of soldiers sent to secure the Great Wall are held up, because they dare not face a fearsome peng that has landed on the wall. Help the soldiers defeat the peng.{^n}
tagRumorOr8DescA=万里の長城の 守備のために 派遣された 兵士の一団が 足止めされている。 長城に 舞い降りた 凶悪なペンに 立ち向かう 勇気が なかったのだ。 兵に手を貸し、ペンを倒せ。{^n}
//tagRumorOr8DescB=A group of soldiers sent to secure the Great Wall were held up, because they did not dare face a fearsome Peng that has landed on the wall. Bring word of their progress and the peng's death to the commander, farther down the wall.{^n}
tagRumorOr8DescB=万里の長城の 守備のために 派遣された 兵士の一団が 足止めされている。 長城に 舞い降りた 凶悪なペンに 立ち向かう 勇気が なかったのだ。 事の成り行きと ペンの死を、 長城の先にいる 司令官に 伝えよ。{^n}
//tagRumorOr8DescC=A group of soldiers sent to secure the Great Wall were held up, because they did not dare face a fearsome Peng that has landed on the wall. Their commander was glad to hear of their progress. He heard nothing of their fear, but no harm is done.{^n}
tagRumorOr8DescC=万里の長城の 守備のために 派遣された 兵士の一団が 足止めされている。 長城に 舞い降りた 凶悪なペンに 立ち向かう 勇気が なかったのだ。 事の成り 行きを聞き、 司令官は 喜んだ。 兵士が 怖気づいて いたことには 耳を貸さ なかったが、 それで不都合は 何もない。{^n}
//tagRumorOr10DescA=There is a wealthy man in Zhidan village named Lu Buwei who seems to be interested in any able traveler. Speak to him again to learn more.{^n}
tagRumorOr10DescA=志丹村に 呂不韋という 富豪がいた。 彼は有能な 旅人に興味が あるようだ。 もう一度 彼に話しかけて みよう。{^n}
//tagRumorOr10DescB=There is a wealthy man in Zhidan village named Lu Buwei who seems to be interested in any able traveler. He mentioned that he greatly desires a valuable item buried deep in a cave in Jingyang Woods – and that he would pay handsomely for it. Find the item and bring it to him.{^n}
tagRumorOr10DescB=志丹村に 呂不韋という 富豪がいた。 彼は有能な 旅人に興味が あるようだ。 浄陽の森の 洞窟の奥に 埋められた 高価な宝物を ひどく欲し がっており、 そのためになら 大金をはたくと 言う。 宝物を 探し出し、 彼に届けよ。{^n}
//tagRumorOr10DescC=There was a wealthy man in Zhidan village named Lu Buwei who greatly desired a valuable item buried deep in a cave in Jingyang Woods. He said he would pay handsomely for it. Lu Buwei proved true to his word.{^n}
tagRumorOr10DescC=志丹村に 呂不韋という 富豪がいた。 彼は浄陽の 森の洞窟の 奥に埋められた 高価な宝物を ひどく 欲しがっており、 そのためになら 大金をはたくと 言った。 その言葉は 本当だった。{^n}
//tagRumorOr11DescA=A local rumor speaks of a giant beast that walks deep in the Jingyang Woods, which flank the road to Chang'an. Search for it in the forest depths.{^n}
tagRumorOr11DescA=噂では、 浄陽の森の 奥深くに、 巨大な獣が 棲息して いるという。 長安行きの 街道から 脇道を辿れば 浄陽の森だ。 森の奥へ行き、 獣を探せ。{^n}
//tagRumorOr11DescB=A giant beast walked deep in the Jingyang Woods. It will trouble lost travelers no more.{^n}
tagRumorOr11DescB=浄陽の森の 奥深くに 巨大な獣がいた。 奴が道に 迷った旅人を 悩ませることは もうない だろう。{^n}
//tagRumorOr12DescA=In the Mausoleum of the Great Emperor, the army of terra cotta soldiers have come to life. They are wreaking havoc in the city of Chang'an. Enter the Mausoleum and put a stop to the chaos.{^n}
tagRumorOr12DescA=始皇帝の御陵で 兵馬俑が 生命を得、 長安の街に 大損害を 与えている。 霊廟に入り、 混乱を鎮めよ。{^n}
//tagRumorOr12DescB=In the Mausoleum of the Great Emperor, the army of terra cotta soldiers had come to life. An evil wraith named Bandari was apparently behind this mischief. Thankfully, no more statues will rise and walk due to his magic. Return to the captain Ma Feibai with the news.{^n}
tagRumorOr12DescB=始皇帝の御陵で、 兵馬俑が 生命を得た。 バンダリーなる 幽霊が、 裏で糸を 引いていた。 ありがたや、 奴の魔法で 彫像が 動き出すことは もうない だろう。 隊長の 馬非百に 報告せよ。{^n}
//tagRumorOr12DescC=In the Mausoleum of the Great Emperor, the army of terra cotta soldiers had come to life. An evil wraith named Bandari was apparently behind this mischief. Thankfully, no more statues will rise and walk due to his magic.{^n}
tagRumorOr12DescC=始皇帝の御陵で、 兵馬俑が 生命を得た。 バンダリーなる 幽霊が、 裏で糸を 引いていた。 ありがたや、 奴の魔法で 彫像が 動き出すことは もうない だろう。{^n}
//tagRumorOr13DescA=Many terra cotta soldiers are loose in the city. The guards are superstitious and won't go near them, so they cannot secure the rest of the city. Defeat these clay soldiers throughout Chang'an.{^n}
tagRumorOr13DescA=数多の兵馬俑が 街に解き放たれた。 守備兵は 迷信に囚われて 奴らに 近づこうとせず、 街は危険に 晒されている。 長安中の 土人形を倒せ。{^n}
//tagRumorOr13DescB=Many terra cotta soldiers were loose in the city. The guards were superstitious and wouldn't go near them. With the clay soldiers gone, the soldiers can return to defending the city. Return to the guard Wai Zhen for your reward.{^n}
tagRumorOr13DescB=数多の兵馬俑が 街に解き放たれた。 守備兵は 迷信に囚われて 奴らに 近づこうと しない。 土人形が いなくなったので、 兵士たちも 街の守りに 復帰するだろう。 副官の 衛鎮の 元へ行き、 褒美を貰おう。{^n}
//tagRumorOr13DescC=Many terra cotta soldiers were loose in the city. The superstitious guards wouldn't go near them, so they were unable to secure the rest of the city. The reward for removing the clay soldiers was generous.{^n}
tagRumorOr13DescC=数多の兵馬俑が 街に解き放たれた。 迷信深い 守備兵たちは 奴らに 近づこうとせず、 街は危険に 晒されていた。 土人形を 退治した 見返りに、 気前よく 褒美をくれた。{^n}
//tagRumorOr14DescA=A man named Liu Xu described a cave behind a waterfall of the Jinghe River, where the ancestors of his family were interred. Evil spirits now attack any who go near, and the man cannot revere his ancestors. Find the cave and defeat the spirits.{^n}
tagRumorOr14DescA=劉昫という 男によれば、 精河の滝裏の 洞窟に、 彼の先祖が 祀られて いると言う。 しかし邪霊が 近づく人に 襲いかかり、 お詣りできずに 困っている。 洞窟へ行き、 幽霊を倒せ。{^n}
//tagRumorOr14DescB=A man named Liu Xu described a cave behind a waterfall of the Jinghe River, where the ancestors of his family were interred. Evil spirits had infested the cave, but his family may now return there to make offerings. Speak to Liu Xu with the news.{^n}
tagRumorOr14DescB=劉昫という 男によれば、 精河の滝裏の 洞窟に、 彼の先祖が 祀られて いると言う。 彼は邪霊の 出没に悩まされて いたが、 これでまた お詣りに 来ることが できるだろう。 劉昫に報告せよ。{^n}
//tagRumorOr14DescC=A man named Liu Xu described a cave behind a waterfall of the Jinghe River, where the ancestors of his family were interred. Evil spirits had infested the cave, but his family may now return there to making offerings.{^n}
tagRumorOr14DescC=劉昫という 男によれば、 精河の滝裏の 洞窟に、 彼の先祖が 祀られて いると言う。 彼は邪霊の 出没に悩まされて いたが、 これでまた お詣りに 来ることが できるだろう。{^n}
//tagRumorOr15DescA=A peaceful Taoist mage lived by himself in this valley. He used to visit the village monthly, but no one has seen him for some time. Look for his home in the Jinghe Valley.{^n}
tagRumorOr15DescA=穏やかな仙人が、 谷で一人住まい していた。 彼は毎月 村を訪れて いたのだが、 ここ数ヶ月は 姿を見せない のだという。 精河渓谷で 彼の家を探せ。{^n}
//tagRumorOr15DescB=A peaceful Taoist mage lived by himself in this valley. Nobody had seen him – and with good reason. His home was burnt and ravaged by the monsters.{^n}
tagRumorOr15DescB=穏やかな仙人が、 谷で一人住まい していた。 彼が姿を 見せなかった のには理由が あった。 彼の家は 怪物に火を 放たれ、 破壊されて いたのだ。{^n}
//tagRumorOr16DescA=A strange girl on the mountain path did not fear the monsters. She said she could not be harmed. She spoke of her sisters that lived in the Jinghe Wetlands. Look for her sisters there.{^n}
tagRumorOr16DescA=不思議なことに、 山道の少女は 怪物をちっとも 恐れて いなかった。 怪物たちは 彼女には 危害を加えない のだと言う。 彼女は 精河湿地に住む 妹たちについて 語った。 妹たちを探せ。{^n}
//tagRumorOr16DescB=A strange girl on the mountain path did not fear the monsters. She said she could not be harmed. By the cottage you found one of her sisters terribly upset. The third sister is in trouble. Find and save her.{^n}
tagRumorOr16DescB=不思議なことに、 山道の少女は 怪物をちっとも 恐れて いなかった。 怪物たちは 彼女には 危害を加えない のだと言う。 小屋の傍にいた 妹の1人は ひどく動転 していた。 末の妹が 窮地に陥って いるのだ。 彼女を救え。{^n}
//tagRumorOr16DescBAlternate=A beautiful young woman stood by a humble cottage, terribly upset. Her sister is in trouble. Find and save her.{^n}
tagRumorOr16DescBAlternate=若く美しい女性が、 粗末な小屋の 傍でひどく 動転していた。 彼女の妹が 窮地に陥って いるのだ。 彼女を救え。{^n}
//tagRumorOr16DescC=Once safe, the woman told her story : long ago, the great sage Lao-Jun traveled the lands as a beggar. None in the land offered him food or shelter - none but these three good sisters. In return, he gave them each a magic seed, and said that when they ate the seeds, no harm would come to them, so long as they did no harm. Alas, Ru Zhao saw a tiger-man about to kill a deer, and she struck and killed it. The spell was broken, her immortality lost. Bring this news to her sister, Li Hua.{^n}
tagRumorOr16DescC=救い出された後、 彼女は語り始めた。 その昔、 大賢人 太上老君は、 物乞いに 身をやつして 諸国を旅した。 乞食姿の彼に、 誰も食べ物や 宿を提供 しようとは しなかったが、 ただ善良なる 三姉妹だけは 違った。 彼はお礼として、 三姉妹に 魔法の種を 与えて こう言った。 「この種を 食せば、 汝らが他者を 傷つけぬ 限り、 何人も汝らを 傷つける ことはない」と。 だが何たることか、 茹昭は 虎人間が 鹿を殺そうと しているのを見て、 虎人間に 襲いかかり、 殺して しまったのだ。 老君の魔法は 消え失せ、 彼女は不死身では なくなって しまった。 姉の莉花に 報告せよ。{^n}
//tagRumorOr16DescD=Long ago, the great sage Lao-Jun traveled the lands as a beggar. None in the land offered him food or shelter - none but these three good sisters. In return, he gave them each a magic seed, and said that when they ate the seeds, no harm would come to them, so long as they did no harm. Alas, Ru Zhao saw a tiger-man about to kill a deer, and she struck and killed it. The spell was broken, her immortality lost. {^n}
tagRumorOr16DescD=その昔、 大賢人 太上老君は、 物乞いに 身をやつして 諸国を旅した。 乞食姿の彼に、 誰も食べ物や 宿を提供 しようとは しなかったが、 ただ善良なる 三姉妹だけは 違った。 彼はお礼として、 三姉妹に 魔法の種を 与えて こう言った。 「この種を 食せば、 汝らが他者を 傷つけぬ 限り、 何人も汝らを 傷つける ことはない」と。 だが何たることか、 茹昭は 虎人間が 鹿を殺そうと しているのを見て、 虎人間に 襲いかかり、 殺して しまったのだ。 老君の魔法は 消え失せ、 彼女は不死身では なくなって しまった。{^n}
//tagRumorOr17DescA=A man who was once a powerful general has fled to the wilderness, where he contemplates the passage of existence. He mentioned that he abandoned his weapons and armor in a cave nearby. Look for them there.{^n}
tagRumorOr17DescA=男はかつて 有力な将軍 であったが、 荒野へと 逃げ去り、 生命の 行く末について 熟考していた。 彼は近くの 洞窟に武器と 防具を捨てた と言った。 洞窟へ探しに 行こう。{^n}
//tagRumorOr17DescB=A man who was once a powerful general has fled to the wilderness, where he contemplates the passage of existence. You found his abandoned weapons and armor in a cave.{^n}
tagRumorOr17DescB=男はかつて 有力な将軍 であったが、 荒野へと 逃げ去り、 生命の 行く末について 熟考していた。 洞窟に 捨てられていた 武器と防具を 見つけた。{^n}

//tagRumorGr1Level=Helos
tagRumorGr1Level=ヘロス
//tagRumorGr2Level=Sparta
tagRumorGr2Level=スパルタ
//tagRumorGr3Level=Megara
tagRumorGr3Level=メガラ
//tagRumorGr4Level=Delphi
tagRumorGr4Level=デルフォイ
//tagRumorGr5Level=Athens
tagRumorGr5Level=アテネ
//tagRumorGr6Level=Knossos
tagRumorGr6Level=クノッソス
//tagRumorEg1Level=Rhakotis
tagRumorEg1Level=ラコティス
//tagRumorEg2Level=Lower Nile
tagRumorEg2Level=ナイル下流
//tagRumorEg3Level=Memphis
tagRumorEg3Level=メンフィス
//tagRumorEg4Level=Giza
tagRumorEg4Level=ギゼ
//tagRumorEg5Level=Fayum Oasis
tagRumorEg5Level=ファイユーム オアシス
//tagRumorEg6Level=Thebes
tagRumorEg6Level=テーベ
//tagRumorOr1Level=Babylon
tagRumorOr1Level=バビロン
//tagRumorOr2Level=Silk Road
tagRumorOr2Level=シルクロード
//tagRumorOr3Level=Great Wall
tagRumorOr3Level=万里の長城
//tagRumorOr4Level=Chang'an
tagRumorOr4Level=長安
//tagRumorOr5Level=Qiyun
tagRumorOr5Level=齊雲
//tagRumorOr6Level=Forest of the Ancients
tagRumorOr6Level=太古の森林
//tagQuestItem01=Eye of Chaos
tagQuestItem01=混沌の眼
//tagQuestItem02=Hand of Balance
tagQuestItem02=調和の手
//tagQuestItem03=Scroll of Invocation
tagQuestItem03=祈祷の巻物
//tagQuestItem04=Cuneiform Tablet
tagQuestItem04=楔形文字の刻板
//tagQuestItem05=Sacred Olive Branch
tagQuestItem05=聖なるオリーブの枝
//tagQuestItem06=Scepter of Eternity
tagQuestItem06=不滅の錫杖
//tagQuestItem07=Sickle of Kronos
tagQuestItem07=クロノスの鎌

//tagQuestItemDescr01=A wild fire burns in the heart of the luminous green stone.
tagQuestItemDescr01=緑色に輝く石の中心で 激しい炎が燃えている
//tagQuestItemDescr02=The Hand is strangely weighty, as if under the constant pull of some unseen world.
tagQuestItemDescr02=この杖はやけに重たい。 まるで見えない世界から 引力を受けているようだ
//tagQuestItemDescr03=The ancient papyrus is covered with heavy, ornate pictograms.
tagQuestItemDescr03=古代のパピルスはびっしりと 華麗な絵文字で 埋め尽くされている
//tagQuestItemDescr04=The strange wedge-shaped markings in the clay resemble birds' feet.
tagQuestItemDescr04=粘土板の奇妙な 楔形の模様は 鳥の足跡のようだ
//tagQuestItemDescr05=A small branch taken from the sacred olive tree above Helicos Pass.
tagQuestItemDescr05=ヘリコス山道の 聖なるオリーブの樹から 取った小枝
//tagQuestItemDescr06=Formed from the Eye of Chaos and the Hand of Balance, the scepter seems to tremble gently with the vast power it contains.
tagQuestItemDescr06=混沌の眼と調和の手から 作られた錫杖は、 莫大な力を内に秘め、 静かに 震えているようだ
//tagQuestItemDescr07=A legendary artifact of mysterious and unspeakable power.
tagQuestItemDescr07=神秘的で言語に絶する力を 持った伝説の秘宝

//tagQuestObject01=Eternity Altar
tagQuestObject01=不滅の祭壇
//tagQuestObject02=Portal to Babylon
tagQuestObject02=バビロンへのポータル
//tagQuestObject03=Portal to Thebes
tagQuestObject03=テーベへのポータル
//tagQuestObject04=Typhon's Portal
tagQuestObject04=テュポンのポータル
//tagQuestObject05=Sacred Olive Tree
tagQuestObject05=聖なるオリーブの樹
//tagQuestObject06=Khufu's Sarcophagus
tagQuestObject06=クフ王の石棺
//tagJournalItem01=Dowry Necklace
tagJournalItem01=結婚祝いのネックレス
//tagJournalItem02=Chiron's Bow
tagJournalItem02=ケイロンの弓
//tagJournalItem03=Staff of Xanthippus
tagJournalItem03=クサンティッポスの杖
//tagJournalItem04=Family Sword of Anherru
tagJournalItem04=アンヘルの伝家の宝剣
//tagJournalItem05=Staff of Khufu
tagJournalItem05=クフ王の杖
//tagJournalItem06=Jade Figurine
tagJournalItem06=翡翠の彫像

//tagJournalItemDescr01=A simple necklace, wrought of fine gold.
tagJournalItemDescr01=純金製の シンプルな ネックレス
//tagJournalItemDescr02=This sturdy and beautiful bow appears to have been carefully built by its owner.
tagJournalItemDescr02=この頑丈で美しい弓は、 その持ち主から 丁寧に作られたようだ
//tagJournalItemDescr03=The magical healer's staff fills all who touch it with a warm, soothing glow.
tagJournalItemDescr03=治療師の魔法の杖に 触れた者は、 暖かく心休まる 光で満たされる
//tagJournalItemDescr04=Although scratched and old, this fine sword is covered with intricate hieroglyphs and designs.
tagJournalItemDescr04=古くて傷もあるが、 この立派な剣は 複雑な神聖文字と 模様とに覆われている
//tagJournalItemDescr05=The great hero's staff is covered with precious stones and intricate markings, and a dusky sense of power hangs around it.
tagJournalItemDescr05=この偉大な英雄の杖は、 高価な宝石と 複雑な模様で覆われ、 陰鬱な権力意識が まとわりついている
//tagJournalItemDescr06=Ancient and graceful, the tiny jade carving glows coolly in almost any light.
tagJournalItemDescr06=古く上品で小さな 翡翠の彫刻は、 どんな光の下でも 冷たく輝いている

//tagEndPortal=Victory Portal
tagEndPortal=ヴィクトリー ポータル
//tagEndChest01=Typhon's Essence
tagEndChest01=テュポンの実体
//tagEndChest02=Mystical Orb
tagEndChest02=神秘のオーブ
//tagJournalUpdate=Side Quest Updated :
tagJournalUpdate=サイド クエストの更新 :
//tagQuestUpdate=Main Quest Updated :
tagQuestUpdate=メイン クエストの更新 :
//tagQuestUnsolvable=Cannot Complete :
tagQuestUnsolvable=未完了のクエスト :
//tagQuestAdded=Quest Added :
tagQuestAdded=クエスト追加 :
//tagQuestComplete=Quest Complete :
tagQuestComplete=クエスト完了 :
//tagLogUnsolvable=This quest cannot be completed in this multiplayer game.
tagLogUnsolvable=このクエストはマルチプレイヤーゲームでは完了しません
//tagQError01=Quest {%t0} Reset
tagQError01=クエスト {%t0} リセット
//tagQError02=Invalid Quest Data
tagQError02=クエスト データ誤り
//tagQError03=Quest State Reset
tagQError03=クエスト状態リセット
//tagRewardGold=Gold
tagRewardGold=ゴールド
//tagRewardExperience=Experience
tagRewardExperience=経験値
//tagRewardAttribute=Attribute Points
tagRewardAttribute=属性 ポイント
//tagRewardSkill=Skill Point(s)
tagRewardSkill=スキル ポイント
//tagReward=Reward :
tagReward=報酬 :
//tagLogReward=You Will Receive :
tagLogReward=達成時の報酬 :
//tagLogRewardComplete=Rewarded :
tagLogRewardComplete=受取済の報酬 :
//tagLogGold=Gold
tagLogGold=ゴールド
//tagLogExperience=Experience
tagLogExperience=経験値
//tagLogAttPoints=Attribute Points
tagLogAttPoints=属性 ポイント
//tagLogSkillPoints=Skill Point(s)
tagLogSkillPoints=スキル ポイント
//tagLogInventoryBag=Inventory Bag
tagLogInventoryBag=手持ち袋
//tagLogInventoryBagDesc=This bag adds an additional40slotstoyourinventory.
tagLogInventoryBagDesc=この袋はあなたの インベントリに 40スロットを加えます
//tagLogMagicWeapon=Magical Weapon
tagLogMagicWeapon=魔法の武器
//tagLogMagicArmor=Magical Armor
tagLogMagicArmor=魔法の防具
//tagLogMagicGeneric01=Magical Item
tagLogMagicGeneric01=魔法のアイテム
//tagLogMagicGeneric02=Magical Equipment
tagLogMagicGeneric02=魔法の装備
//tagLogRelic=Completed Relic
tagLogRelic=完成したレリック
//tagLogRelicShard=Relic Shard
tagLogRelicShard=レリックの破片
//tagLogCharm=Completed Charm
tagLogCharm=完成したチャーム
//tagLogCharmShard=Partial Charm
tagLogCharmShard=チャームの一部
//tagLogJewelry=Magical Jewelry
tagLogJewelry=魔法の装飾品
//tagLogHealth=Health Point Bonus
tagLogHealth=ヘルス ポイント ボーナス
tagLog Health=ヘルス ポイント ボーナス
//tagLogEnergy=Energy Point Bonus
tagLogEnergy=エナジー ポイント ボーナス
//tagLogResistance=Bonus Resistance
tagLogResistance=ボーナス耐性
//tagLogRing=Powerful Ring
tagLogRing=強力な指輪
//tagLogAmulet=Powerful Amulet
tagLogAmulet=強力なお守り
//tagJG10RewardNormal=+75 Health
tagJG10RewardNormal=+75 ヘルス
//tagJG10RewardEpic=+150 Health
tagJG10RewardEpic=+150 ヘルス
//tagJG10RewardLegendary=+200 Health
tagJG10RewardLegendary=+200 ヘルス
//tagJG14RewardNormal01=+5% Permanent Fire Resistance
tagJG14RewardNormal01=+5% 永久的な炎耐性
//tagJG14RewardNormal02=+5% Permanent Cold Resistance
tagJG14RewardNormal02=+5% 永久的な冷気耐性
//tagJG14RewardNormal03=+5% Permanent Lightning Resistance
tagJG14RewardNormal03=+5% 永久的な雷耐性
//tagJG14RewardNormal04=+5% Permanent Poison Resistance
tagJG14RewardNormal04=+5% 永久的な毒耐性
//tagJG14RewardEpic01=+7% Permanent Fire Resistance
tagJG14RewardEpic01=+7% 永久的な炎耐性
//tagJG14RewardEpic02=+7% Permanent Cold Resistance
tagJG14RewardEpic02=+7% 永久的な冷気耐性
//tagJG14RewardEpic03=+7% Permanent Lightning Resistance
tagJG14RewardEpic03=+7% 永久的な雷耐性
//tagJG14RewardEpic04=+7% Permanent Poison Resistance
tagJG14RewardEpic04=+7% 永久的な毒耐性
//tagJG14RewardLegendary01=+5% Permanent Elemental Resistance
tagJG14RewardLegendary01=+5% 永久的なエレメンタル耐性
//tagJO06RewardNormal=+3 Bonus Damage to all Weapons
tagJO06RewardNormal=+3 全ての武器にボーナス ダメージ
//tagJO06RewardEpic=+5 Bonus Damage to all Weapons
tagJO06RewardEpic=+5 全ての武器にボーナス ダメージ
//tagJO06RewardLegendary=+8 Bonus Damage to all Weapons
tagJO06RewardLegendary=+8 全ての武器にボーナス ダメージ
//tagRewardHealthMana=Health and Energy Restored
tagRewardHealthMana=ヘルスとエナジーを全快
I=I
II=II
III=III
IV=IV
V=V
VI=VI
VII=VII
VIII=VIII
IX=IX
X=X
XI=XI
XII=XII
XIII=XIII
XIV=XIV
XV=XV