// Do not directly modify the content of this file, it is auto generated. Modify the source instead.
// Encoding: utf-16
x2tagQuestItem01=Golden Sickle
x2tagQuestItemDescr01=A fine tool with a golden blade, as used by celtic druids.
x2tagQuestItem02=Mistletoe of Nerthus
x2tagQuestItemDescr02=The sacred mistletoe of the earth goddess glows with primordial power.
x2tagQuestItem03=Rune Tablet
x2tagQuestItemDescr03=An incomplete stone tablet engraved with Dvergr markings.
x2tagQuestItem04=Rune Tablet
x2tagQuestItemDescr04=This looks like the bottom half of a tablet with Dvergr writing.
x2tagQuestItem05=Kornwyf Scythe
x2tagQuestItemDescr05=The demon's scythe is of remarkably good quality.
x2tagQuestItem06=Ornate Seal Ring
x2tagQuestItemDescr06=The ghost's ring shows a seal, probably belonging to his family.
x2tagQuestItem07=Keg of wine
x2tagQuestItemDescr07=The seal was opened but it is still about half full.
x2tagQuestItem08=Honeycomb
x2tagQuestItemDescr08=Full of golden gooey goodness.
x2tagQuestItem09=Embossed silver plate (1)
x2tagQuestItemDescr09=A large square plate that depicts a person wearing a torc
x2tagQuestItem10=Embossed silver plate (2)
x2tagQuestItemDescr10=A concave relief that shows a wheel surrounded by strange creatures
x2tagQuestItem11=Embossed silver plate (3)
x2tagQuestItemDescr11=A circular plate that depicts a bull and a female warrior
x2tagQuestItem12=Embossed silver plate (4)
x2tagQuestItemDescr12=A cracked plate that shows a large being throwing a small man into a pot
x2tagQuestItem13=Broken Spear
x2tagQuestItemDescr13=This looks like Ylva's weapon... snapped in half.
x2tagQuestItem14=Ancient Breastplate
x2tagQuestItemDescr14=This ancient piece of armor is decorated with intricate symbols.
x2tagQuestItem15=Woolen Scarf
x2tagQuestItemDescr15=A fluffy warm scarf made of sheep's wool.
x2tagQuestItem16=Sheepskin
x2tagQuestItemDescr16=Giesel's fluffy pelt
x2tagQuestItem17=Wolf Skull
x2tagQuestItemDescr17=This must have been a very large specimen
x2tagQuestObject01=Lever
x2tagQuestObject02=Winch
x2tagQuestObject03=Lock
x2tagQuestObject04=Key
x2tagQAct05=Act V
x2tagXXII=XXII
x2tagx2Q02_Title=The Warrior Princess
x2tagXXIII=XXIII
x2tagChestZZ=Dark Chest of Wonders
x2tagParchmentTitle01=Behind the wall
x2tagParchmentBody01=Verily, I tell you! The most dangerous monsters this world has ever seen, but also the most incredible treasure, can be found at{^n}{^n}{^f}(Please download the Premium Lore DLC to read the rest of this scroll.)
x2tagParchmentTitle02=Actor's note
x2tagParchmentBody02=Like a sailor runs to the siren {^n}Like a moth flies to the fire {^n}I know your love brings me to Hades’ door {^n}But still I follow my desire
x2tagParchmentTitle03=Poet's jotting
x2tagParchmentBody03=Oh, I am fierce {^n}and I am feeling mighty {^n}I am an Aphrodite lady {^n}with a seashell ...strophium?
x2tagParchmentTitleZZ=The Pieces
x2tagParchmentBodyZZ=A great lighthouse will be built by the children of Ptolemy where poor people have unstable walls.{^n}{^n}The Tao is the way, but sometimes one should explore the opposite direction{^n}{^n}The Eye sees a path in more than one chalice.{^n}{^n}And Artemis is known to have a good influence on her twin.
x2tagQuestItem18=Stolen Barrel
x2tagQuestItemDescr18=A barrel of fresh celtic beer
x2tagQuestItem19=Stolen Box
x2tagQuestItemDescr19=A wooden box that faintly smells of bacon
x2tagQuestItem20=Stolen Bundle
x2tagQuestItemDescr20=A bundle of cloths with different colorful patterns
x2tagQuestItem21=Audhild's Permit
x2tagQuestItemDescr21=Grants ownership of the Kaupangr smithy
x2tagQuestItem22=Mead of Valhöll
x2tagQuestItemDescr22=The drink of the Einherjar from the udder of Heidrun
x2tagQuestItem23=Mead of Poetry
x2tagQuestItemDescr23=A legendary substance said to grant wisdom and inspiration
x2tagQuestItem24=Blacksteel Ingot
x2tagQuestItemDescr24=A piece of strange metal with a suface like a black mirror
x2tagQuestItem25=Lupine Necklace
x2tagQuestItemDescr25=A beautiful necklace made out of wolf claws and small sea shells.
x2tagQuestItem26=Lupine Necklace Design
x2tagQuestItemDescr26=Sketches in coal of a necklace featuring three large claws.
x2tagQuestItem27=The Nordic Mystery
x2tagQuestItemDescr27=Instructions for putting together a forbidden spell.
x2tagQuestItem28=Spell Piece
x2tagQuestItemDescr28=The head of a spell scroll.
x2tagQuestItem29=Spell Piece
x2tagQuestItemDescr29=Part of a spell written on stretched hide.
x2tagQuestItem30=Spell Piece
x2tagQuestItemDescr30=The bottom end of a spell scroll.
x2tagQuestItem34=Spell of Pieces
x2tagQuestItemDescr34="Odor"
x2tagQuestItem31=Loki's Wand
x2tagQuestItemDescr31=A small staff that may be key to some of the trickster's powers.
x2tagQuestItem32=Fire Relic
x2tagQuestItemDescr32=A transparent stone with a fiery glow in its heart.
x2tagQuestItem33=Ichthian Relic
x2tagQuestItemDescr33=An ancient cube of unknown origin.
x2tagx2Q01_Title=Troubles of a New Age
x2tagx2Q01_Desc_A=After your long trek through the Underworld you have arrived in a sunny Corinth where a large festival is to be held to celebrate the defeat of the monster army. Speaking to the aristocrat Ariston, however, you learned that there seems to be some trouble in the northern harbor, possibly a pirate raid! Ariston asked you to go to the harbor of Lechaion and investigate. A hero's work is never done.
x2tagx2Q01_Obj_A=Find the dockmaster in Lechaion harbor
x2tagx2Q01_Desc_B=After your long trek through the Underworld you have a arrived in a sunny Corinth where a large festival is to be held to celebrate the defeat of the monster army. You get charged by Ariston to investigate reports of turmoil in the harbor of Lechaion where you find Haimon, a very scared dockmaster. Just as he is about to speak a giant sea monster emerges from the sea and attacks him. Slay the terrible beast.
x2tagx2Q01_Obj_B=Slay the Ketos
x2tagx2Q01_Obj_C=Speak with Ariston
x2tagx2Q01_Desc_C=After your long trek through the Underworld you have a arrived in a sunny Corinth where a large festival is to be held to celebrate the defeat of the monster army. You were charged by Ariston to investigate reports of turmoil in the harbor of Lechaion which turned out to be a raid by sea creatures. After a fierce battle you slew their pet Ketos and returned to Ariston, who was very pleased, while your fame grows as another legendary beast is slain.
x2tagx2Q01_Title=The Warrior Princess
x2tagx2Q02_Desc_A=In Corinth you were approached by Ylva, a noble hailing from the distant north, who has come all the way to Greece to find you. The strange gods her people worship seem to follow Hades' example and are attacking the lands of the Norsemen. She bids you journey north and meet her in a town called Glauberg. However, since Lechaion harbor is destroyed you must go to Kenchreai, the other port of mighty Corinth, and take the boat from there.
x2tagx2Q02_Obj_A=Go east to Kenchreai and find a boat to take you north.
x2tagx2Q02_Obj_B=Ask for directions to Glauberg.
x2tagx2Q02_Desc_B=Having agreed to help Ylva in the struggle against the Aesir, you have taken a long sea voyage from Greece to the forested lands of the Celts. From here on out the journey will go by foot. You have agreed to meet up with Ylva in the celtic hill fort of Glauberg, which lies to north beyond the vast Hercynian Forest.
x2tagx2Q02_Obj_C=Talk to the lookout on Lemberg mountain
x2tagx2Q02_Obj_D=Go north to Glauberg
x2tagx2Q02_Desc_C=Having agreed to help Ylva in the struggle against the Aesir, you hve taken a long sea voyage from Greece to the forested lands of the Celts. Eventually you have found your way to Glauberg where you had agreed to meet. There Ylva revealed that she had chosen this meeting place for more reasons than one.
x2tagx2Q03_Title=The Power of Nerthus
x2tagXXIV=XXIV
x2tagx2Q03_Desc_A=A mysterious artifact that Ylva believes will greatly aid her people is kept by the Cult of Nerthus, a twisted and powerful nature cult that holds sway over the wildlands beyond Glauberg. You must go to their undeground sanctuary in the Suebi Lakelands and slay the four Elders that guard the artifact. Doing so will not only further your own cause, but also greatly please the Glauberg Prince, to whom the cult has been as a thorn in his side for a long time.
x2tagx2Q03_Obj_A=Kill the Ancient of the Sky
x2tagx2Q03_Obj_B=Kill the Ancient of the Lake
x2tagx2Q03_Obj_C=Kill the Ancient of the Wild
x2tagx2Q03_Obj_D=Kill the Ancient of the Soil
x2tagx2Q03_Obj_E=Retrieve the Nerthus Artifact
x2tagx2Q03_Desc_B=A magical mistletoe that Ylva believes will greatly aid her people was kept by the Cult of Nerthus, a twisted and powerful nature cult. You have retrieved the relic from their underground sanctuary and must now journey further north and deliver it to her father King Gylfi, in the cold lands of Scandia, where she is already preparing her soldiers.
x2tagx2Q03_Obj_F=Go north to the Zealand coast
x2tagx2Q03_Obj_G=Find all three pieces of stolen goods and bring them to Wodbald
x2tagx2Q03_Obj_H=Take the boat to Gylfis Settlement
x2tagx2Q03_Obj_I=Talk to King Gylfi
x2tagx2Q03_Desc_C=A magical mistletoe that Ylva believes will greatly aid her people was kept by the Cult of Nerthus, a twisted and powerful nature cult. You have retrieved the relic from their underground sanctuary and delivered it to King Gylfi who will let his enchanters examine it. However, another problem has arisen: Ylva never made it home, and was probably taken by the Aesir to be used as a bargaining chip...
x2tagx2Q04_Title=Scandia under Siege
x2tagXXV=XXV
x2tagx2Q04_Desc_A=Ylva is missing and may have been captured. Speaking with King Gylfi, you learned that there is an ancient Aesir shrine to the north where they might have taken her. It may be best to go there and investigate.
x2tagx2Q04_Obj_A=Locate Sithun Shrine
x2tagx2Q04_Obj_B=Explore the shrine
x2tagx2Q04_Obj_C=Return to King Gylfi with your findings
x2tagx2Q04_Desc_B=Ylva is missing. Speaking with King Gylfi, you learned that there was an ancient Aesir shrine to the north where they might have taken her. After forcing your way in, you managed to find her broken weapon, suggesting that she had indeed been there but was taken somewhere else. So all you have for the king is bad news.
x2tagx2Q05_Title=The Rescue
x2tagXXVI=XXVI
x2tagx2Q05_Desc_A=It looks very much like Ylva has been captured and abducted by the Aesir. You should discuss with King Gylfi about what can be done.
x2tagx2Q05_Obj_A=Talk to King Gylfi
x2tagx2Q05_Desc_B=It looks very much like Ylva has been captured and abducted by the Aesir. You decided to travel to Asgard, the homeland of the Aesir, in hope of finding her there. The road is long however, and first you must brave the ancient Dvergr Halls of the west in order to find passage unto Yggdrasil, the cosmic tree.
x2tagx2Q05_Obj_B=Talk to Nidbald about ferrying you to the Dark Lands
x2tagx2Q05_Obj_C=Talk to Audhild in Kaupangr
x2tagx2Q05_Desc_C=You decided to travel to Asgard, the homeland of the Aesir, in hopes of finding Ylva there. The road is long however, and first you must brave the ancient Dvergr Halls under the mountain in order to find passage unto Yggdrasil, the cosmic tree.{^n}Having arrived at Kaupangr, you learn that the Dvergr Halls are closed to the outside world. However, a tribe of Fjord on the opposite side may have found the key...
x2tagx2Q05_Obj_D=Find the Ichthian Relic
x2tagx2Q05_Obj_E=Open the South Gate
x2tagx2Q05_Desc_D=You decided to travel to Asgard, the homeland of the Aesir, in hopes of finding Ylva there. The road is long however, and first you must brave the ancient Dvergr Halls unnder the mountain in order to find passage unto Yggdrasil, the cosmic tree.{^n}At Kaupangr, you learned that the Dvergr Halls are closed to the outside world. Luckily a nearby tribe of Fjord Ichthians was worshipping the key as an idol. The gate is open, and now you can venture below...
x2tagx2Q05_Obj_F=Explore the Dvergr Halls
x2tagx2Q05_Obj_G=Kill the Fungoid King
x2tagx2Q05_Obj_H=Talk to Dvalinn
x2tagx2Q05_Obj_I=Venture into Asgard
x2tagx2Q05_Desc_E=You decided to travel to Asgard, the homeland of the Aesir, in hopes of finding Ylva there. After a very long journey at sea, below the earth, and on Yggdrasil itself, you finally arrived at your goal. According to King Gylfi, this is where Ylva is imprisoned in Wodan's stronghold Valhöll. Now the two of you must escape.
x2tagx2Q05_Obj_J=Find Ylva
x2tagx2Q05_Obj_K=Escape Asgard
x2tagx2Q05_Desc_F=You decided to travel to Asgard, the homeland of the Aesir, in hopes of finding Ylva there. After a very long journey at sea, below the earth, and on Yggdrasil itself, you finally arrived at your goal and found 'her' in the dungeons.Your escape quickly took a turn for the worst, however, as a confrontation with the Aesir revealed that Ylva has in truth been the trickster god Loki all along, who tricked you into attacking them!
x2tagx2Q06_Title=The Wisest Being
x2tagXXVII=XXVII
x2tagx2Q06_Desc_A=Ylva's true self has been revealed as the trickster Loki who, with your help, has killed the god of beauty and thus set in motion the prophesized events of Ragnarok - the end of all worlds! Then he disappeared, to continue his schemes to some unknown end...
x2tagx2Q06_Obj_A=Talk to Wodan
x2tagx2Q06_Desc_B=Ylva has been revealed as the trickster Loki who, with your help, has set in motion the events of Ragnarok! In a desperate attempt to find and stop Loki before his evil plans come to fruition, Wodan has decided to go on a daring mission to Jotunheim, home of the frost giants, and extract information from Mimer, the wisest of beings. Follow him to the rainbow bridge at Himinbjörg.
x2tagx2Q06_Obj_B=Talk to Heimdall
x2tagx2Q06_Desc_C=Ylva has been revealed as the trickster Loki who, with your help, has set in motion the events of Ragnarok! In a desperate attempt to stop this, Wodan has decided to go on a daring mission to Jotunheim and extract information from Mimer, the wisest of beings. However Loki anticipated this and sabotaged the rainbow bridge, which now serves as an attack route for the waiting Jotuns. Now you must go to Jotunheim and find Mimer while the Aesir fight off the invasion.
x2tagx2Q06_Obj_C=Seek out Mimer
x2tagx2Q06_Desc_D=Ylva had been revealed as the trickster Loki who, with your help, has set in motion the events of Ragnarok! In a desperate attempt to stop this, Wodan had decided to go on a daring mission to Jotunheim and extract information from Mimer, the wisest of beings. However Loki had anticipated this and sabotaged the rainbow bridge, which then served as an attack route for the waiting Jotuns. So you went to find Mimer instead, and eventually managed to defeat him and his tricks.
x2tagx2Q07_Title=The Burning Sword
x2tagXXVIII=XXVIII
x2tagx2Q07_Desc_A=Mimer is defeated, you have prevailed through all his tricks and tests. Now perhaps he will agree to lend his assistance in stopping Loki and Ragnarok.
x2tagx2Q07_Obj_A=Talk to Mimer
x2tagx2Q07_Desc_B=Mimer revealed to you that the attack of the Jotuns is only half of Loki's ill-fated plan for a rule of giants, which is bound to end in universal destruction even if it succeeds. He is now preparing a second attack by the Eldjotuns, the fire giants, with their lord Surtr. To stop this from happening, you must venture through the roots of Yggdrasil, into their home of Muspelheim.
x2tagx2Q07_Obj_B=Find the way into Yggdrasil's Roots
x2tagx2Q07_Obj_C=Travel to Muspelheim
x2tagx2Q07_Obj_D=Find a way into Surt's Fortress of Land's End
x2tagx2Q07_Obj_E=Use the Fire Relic to enter the Fortress
x2tagx2Q07_Obj_F=Find Loki
x2tagx2Q07_Desc_C=Mimer revealed that the attack of the Jotuns is only half of Loki's ill-fated plan for a rule of giants, which is bound to end in universal destruction. He has been preparing a second attack with Surtr, the lord of Muspelheim. Confronting Loki there, you learned that they are in the process of creating a portal that will drown Asgard in fire and lava while leading them right into the Aesir's backs. Get to the top of Land's End and stop Surtr before he can complete the ritual!
x2tagx2Q07_Obj_G=Kill Surtr
x2tagx2Q07_Desc_D=Mimer revealed that the attack of the Jotuns was only half of Loki's ill-fated plan for a rule of giants, which was bound to end in universal destruction. He had been preparing a second attack with Surtr, the lord of Muspelheim, that would have drowned Asgard in fire and lava. After a long battle atop Land's End you finally vanquished Surtr, his ritual unfinished. Thanks to you, the giants' attacks have crumbled, and Loki's plans were foiled. {^n}Ragnarok has been averted! ...for now.
x2tagQuestObject05=Altar to Nerthus
x2tagQuestObject06=South Gate
x2tagQuestObject07=Keystone
x2tagcorinth_hoplite=Corinthian Guard
x2tagkenchreai_captain=Dorieus ~ Trade Ship Captain
x2tagmuspelheim_valkyrie=Eir
x2taghercynian_sentry=Brigarigos ~ Lookout
x2tagSkillOther01=Dvergr Bombs
x2tagSkillOther02=Geyser
x2tagSkillOther03=Summon Spriggling
x2tagSkillOther04=Ignite Foe
x2tagtravelquestion1=Travel to to the North?
x2tagtravelquestion2=Travel back to Kenchreai?
x2tagtravelquestion3=Travel to Scandia?
x2tagtravelquestion4=Travel back to Zealand?
x2tagtravelquestion5=Travel to Kaupangr?
x2tagtravelquestion6=Travel back to Scandia?
x2tagtravelquestion7=Portal to Järnvidjan
x2tagtravelquestion9=Wodan's Portal
x2tagx2SQ01_Title=Festivities
x2tagx2SQ01_Desc_A=There is a festival being prepared in Corinth on occasion of the allied greek victory over the monsters. Representatives from all over the country are in the city and may be interested in hearing about your adventures on Olympus and in Hades. Have a look around and talk to them.
x2tagx2SQ01_Desc_B=There is a festival being prepared in Corinth on occasion of the allied greek victory over the monsters. Representatives from all over the country are in the city, which gave you a chance to meet your old acquaintances General Leonidas and Phaedrus from the Order of Prometheus, as well as talk to the local rulers. They were happy to hear about your victories on Olympus and in Hades.
x2tagx2SQ02_Title=Sciron
x2tagx2SQ02_Desc_A=Demokrites, a rich merchant and oligarch of Corinth, laments that as soon as the countryside is seeing less monsters, bandits are setting up camp again on the narrow Isthmus. One particularly troublesome group gathered around an outlaw called Sciron has established their domain on some rocks on the Saronic coast, overlooking the road to Kenchreai. Defeat the bandit leader Sciron.
x2tagx2SQ02_Desc_B=Demokrites, a rich merchant and oligarch of Corinth, lamented that as soon as the countryside is seeing less monsters, bandits are setting up camp again on the narrow Isthmus. You went and defeated them together with their leader Sciron. Tell Demokrites the news.
x2tagx2SQ02_Desc_C=Demokrites, a rich merchant and oligarch of Corinth, lamented that as soon as the countryside is seeing less monsters, bandits are setting up camp again on the narrow Isthmus. You went and defeated them together with their leader Sciron, so now the trade route is safe again.
x2tagx2SQ03_Title=A Northern Contact
x2tagx2SQ03_Desc_A=Phaedrus mentioned that the Order of Prometheus has a northern agent in Glauberg named Treveros, but that he did not hear anything from him in a while. Find Treveros and find out what he knows about the events in Scandia.
x2tagx2SQ03_Desc_B=Phaedrus mentioned that the Order of Prometheus has a northern agent in Glauberg named Treveros, but that he did not hear anything from him in a while. You found Treveros dead in a cave by the Rhine, most likely slain by the norse warriors who also ambushed you there. Tell Phaedrus in Corinth.
x2tagx2SQ03_Desc_C=Phaedrus mentioned that the Order of Prometheus had a northern agent in Glauberg named Treveros, but that he did not hear anything from him in a while. You found Treveros dead in a cave by the Rhine, most likely slain by the norse warriors who also ambushed you there.
x2tagx2SQ03_DeadTreveros=Dead Promethean
x2tagx2sq04_Title=White Gold
x2tagx2sq04_Desc_A=The Heuneburg mine owner Gorcoun sent you to investigate some kind of trouble in the nearby salt mine, an important source of the city’s wealth. Something is stopping Gorcoun’s workers from mining. Find out what it is and how to get the miners working again.
x2tagx2sq04_Desc_B=There is something wrong about the Heuneburg salt mine, it seems to be possessed by a horrible curse that raises buried workers from the dead. Find the cause to the problem.
x2tagx2sq04_Desc_C=The Heuneburg salt mine seemed to be possessed by a horrible curse that raised buried workers from the dead. It turned out to be the ghost of a dead man haunting the tunnels that caused the problem. When defeated, the ghost left behind a ring. To whom does it belong?
x2tagx2sq04_Desc_D=The Heuneburg salt mine seemed to be possessed by a horrible curse that raised buried workers from the dead. It turned out to be the ghost of a dead man haunting the tunnels that caused the problem. It left behind a ring, which you returned to the mine owner Gorcoun who promised to look for its rightful owner.
x2tagx2sq04_Desc_E=The Heuneburg salt mine seemed to be possessed by a horrible curse that raised buried workers from the dead. It turned out to be the ghost of a dead man haunting the tunnels that caused the problem. It left behind a ring, which the second mine owner's wife Elise identified as her husband's. Grieving and angered by his apparent murder, she was determined to bring his 'friend and business partner' Gorcoun to justice.
x2tagx2SQ05_Title=Heart to Stomach
x2tagx2SQ05_Desc_A=The tanner Orsos in Heuneburg is hungry and looking for his wife Caomine. She may be west of town around the farms.
x2tagx2SQ05_Desc_B=The tanner Orsos in Heuneburg was hungry and looking for his wife Camine. You found her at the edge of the Hercynian forest, allegedly sorting mushrooms in the hut of the local hunter, from where she then headed home.
x2tagx2SQ05_Desc_C=The tanner Orsos in Heuneburg was hungry and looking for his wife Camine. You found her at the edge of the Hercynian forest, allegedly sorting mushrooms in the hut of the local hunter. Hearing about this, Orsos was very pleased and said it would be worth the wait.
x2tagx2sq06_Title=The Golden Sickle
x2tagx2sq06_Desc_A=A druid named Artebudz had his sickle stolen by a huge troll. See if you can find and return it to him.
x2tagx2sq06_Desc_B=A druid named Artebudz had his sickle stolen by none other than the troll king himself. You found it in a hoard in his cave. Return the sickle to Artebudz in his glade.
x2tagx2sq06_Desc_C=A druid named Artebudz had his sickle stolen by none other than the troll king himself. The druid was very impressed and grateful when you returned it to him.
x2tagx2SQ07_Title=Wine from the Rhine
x2tagx2SQ07_Desc_A=The farmer Borbeto in the Rhine valley has the ambitious plan to grow wine in celtic lands, but the first barrel he produced was promptly taken from him by a gang of bandits. Help Borbeto get back his wine while there is still some left.
x2tagx2SQ07_Desc_B=The farmer Borbeto in the Rhine valley has the ambitious plan to grow wine in celtic lands, but the first barrel he produced was promptly taken from him by a gang of bandits. You took it back, however, before they could drink it all. Bring Borbeto his wine.
x2tagx2SQ07_Desc_C=The farmer Borbeto in the Rhine valley has the ambitious plan to grow wine in celtic lands. After you retrieved the first barrel he produced from a gang of bandits, he asked you to take it to the prince's cook Cunobelenus in Glauberg to taste it.
x2tagx2SQ07_Desc_D=The farmer Borbeto in the Rhine valley has the ambitious plan to grow wine in celtic lands. After you retrieved the first barrel he produced from a gang of bandits, he asked you to take it to the prince's cook Cunobelenus in Glauberg to taste it. Apparently the taste was not very impressive, but the cook still traded you supplies for it.
x2tagx2SQ07_Desc_E=The farmer Borbeto in the Rhine valley has the ambitious plan to grow wine in celtic lands. After you retrieved the first barrel he produced from a gang of bandits, he asked you to take it to the prince's cook Cunobelenus in Glauberg to taste it. Apparently the taste was not very impressive, but the cook still traded you some supplies, and Borbeto was happy to hear about it.
x2tagglauberg_cook=Cunobelenus ~ The Prince’s Cook
x2tagx2SQ08_Title=Celtic Plaid
x2tagx2SQ08_Desc_A=You met a joyful, industrious young weaver at her workplace in Glauberg, dreaming of the wide world. If you want to do her a favor, supply her with the dyes she talked about from the foreign countries you have journeyed to: Greek Purple, Egyptian Gold and Asian Royal Blue.
x2tagx2SQ08_Desc_B=You met a joyful, industrious young weaver at her workplace in Glauberg, dreaming of the wide world. The woman is baffled and overjoyed when you were able to help her out with a selection of exotic dyes from your travels.
x2tagx2SQ09_Title=The Troubled Son
x2tagx2SQ09_Desc_A=The local cooper is a hard-working widowed father who is concerned about his teenage son Judoc. After not seeing him in days, he fears that he may have been abducted members of the Cult of Nerthus. Find Judoc.
x2tagx2SQ09_Desc_B=The local cooper was concerned about his teenage son Judoc. He feared that he may have been abducted members of the Cult of Nerthus. In fact he joined them willingly, but soon regretted that decision. Luckily, you were able to save him. Meet Judoc and his father back in Glauberg.
x2tagx2SQ09_Desc_C=The local cooper was concerned about his teenage son Judoc. He feared that he may have been abducted members of the Cult of Nerthus. In fact he joined them willingly, but soon regretted that decision. Luckily, you were able to save him, and the cooper is relieved to have his son back.
x2tagx2SQ10_Title=Little Friends
x2tagx2SQ10_Desc_A=You met a peculiar beekeeper in the Weser Uplands who seems to want you to retrieve some honey from his beehives. He talked about some of them being plundered by bears.
x2tagx2SQ10_Desc_B=You met a peculiar beekeeper in the Weser Uplands who seems to want you to retrieve some honey from his beehives. You got the honey just before a group of bears could get their paws on it. Take it back to the beekeeper.
x2tagx2SQ10_Desc_C=You met a peculiar beekeeper in the Weser Uplands who wanted you to retrieve some honey from his beehives. You got the honey just before a group of bears could get their paws on it, and the beekeeper was grateful.
x2tagx2sq11_Title=The Kornwyf's Scythe
x2tagx2sq11_Desc_A=The Kornwyf you fought in the Heathlands dropped a horrid but formidably sharp scythe. Maybe this could be of use to someone.
x2tagx2sq11_Desc_B=The Kornwyf you fought in the Heathlands dropped a horrid but formidably sharp scythe. You gave it to a struggling farmer who can hopefully make good use of it.
x2tagx2SQ12_Title=The Trapped Nixie
x2tagx2SQ12_Desc_A=The spirit of what is left of a small drying bog asked for your help in crossing the Bilwis-infested heath to the next big body of water. She would certainly be grateful if you escorted her to the Lakelands.
x2tagx2SQ12_Desc_B=The spirit of what is left of a small drying bog asked for your help in crossing the Bilwis-infested heath to the next big body of water in the Lakelands. Unfortunately your recent attempt at this proved too much for her, and she was forced back to her pond.
x2tagx2SQ12_Desc_C=The spirit of what was left of a small drying bog asked for your help in crossing the Bilwis-infested heath to the next big body of water in the Lakelands. After reaching her new home with your aid, she was filled with joy and gratitude.
x2tagx2SQ13_Title=Fir Cone Liquor
x2tagx2SQ13_Desc_A=Nidbald, the captain who sails the route from Gylfi's settlement to the north, does not offer his services freely. Like his brother, Nidbald has a taste for alcoholic beverages and demanded you find him a bottle of Fir Cone Liquor first.
x2tagx2SQ13_Desc_B=Nidbald, the captain who sails the route from Gylfi's settlement to the north, did not want to offer his services freely but demanded you fetch him a bottle of Fir Cone Liquor first. Unfortunately for him, King Gylfi was not very pleased with that attitude towards their hero and ordered him to do it.
x2tagx2sq14_Title=The Magic Cauldron
x2tagx2sq14_Desc_A=Ljotbjörg, the apprentice to the scandian Völva, is working to assemble a mysterious cauldron that has been taken apart and scattered all around germanic lands. But in order to finish it she needs four more parts. See if you can find them.
x2tagx2sq14_Desc_B=Ljotbjörg, the apprentice to the scandian Völva, is working to assemble a mysterious cauldron that has been taken apart and scattered around germanic lands. But in order to finish it she needs four more parts, which you have all managed to find. Deliver the parts to her in Gylfi's settlement.
x2tagx2sq14_Desc_C=Ljotbjörg, the apprentice to the scandian Völva, has been working to assemble a mysterious cauldron that has been taken apart and scattered around germanic lands. With your help, she was able to finish it and share with you some of its arcane powers.
x2tagx2sq15_Title=The Restless King
x2tagx2sq15_Desc_A=Etheltrud claims to be a descendant from The Great King, although no one believes her. To prove it she is looking for an item that resembles her family heirloom. Search the tomb of the Great King for something that may fit this description.
x2tagx2sq15_Desc_B=Etheltrud claims to be a descendant from The Great King, although no one believes her. To prove it she is looking for an item that resembles her family heirloom. In the undead king’s grave, you found an ancient breastplate that could be what she is looking for. Bring it back to her in Gylfi's settlement.
x2tagx2sq15_Desc_C=Etheltrud claimed to be a descendant from The Great King, but no one believed her. With your help, she was able to prove it when you went into the undead king’s grave and retrieved an ancient piece of armor that matched her family heirloom.
x2tagx2sq16_Title=The Survivor
x2tagx2sq16_Desc_A=Aslind, a scared survivor of a recent Einherjar attack, is looking for her husband, hoping that he survived as well. Look for clues in the vincinity of the destroyed village.
x2tagx2sq16_Desc_B=Aslind, a scared survivor of a recent Einherjar attack, is looking for her husband, hoping that he survived as well. Unfortunately that was not the case. Take his scarf and bring it to Aslind.
x2tagx2sq16_Desc_C=Aslind, a scared survivor of a recent Einherjar attack, was looking for her husband, hoping that he survived as well. Unfortunately that was not the case.
x2tagx2sq16_Desc_D=Aslind, a scared survivor of the 'Einherjar' attack on her scandian village, was looking for her husband until you had to tell her that he did not make it. However you were able to provide her with some solace by telling her about the true nature of the attacks, which turned her despair into righteous anger instead.
x2tagSQ16DeadHusband=Hunter's corpse
x2tagx2sq17_Title=Giesel
x2tagx2sq17_Desc_A=A panicked man called Laidulf is missing someone dear to him. Giesel ran off into the woods in spite of his objections, and he is very afraid that the wolves might get her, but also too scared to follow. Follow his directions and find his dear Giesel.
x2tagx2sq17_Desc_B=A panicked man called Laidulf is missing what turned out to be a sheep that ran off into the woods. You found Giesel grazing peacefully in a small glade. Escort her back to safety before the wolves get her after all.
x2tagx2sq17_Desc_C=A panicked man called Laidulf was missing what turned out to be a sheep that ran off into the woods. Unfortunately you were not able to prevent his fears from coming true, and the wolves made short work of his dear Giesel. All that is left of her now is a very fluffy pelt.
x2tagx2sq17_Desc_D=A panicked man called Laidulf was missing what turned out to be a sheep that ran off into the woods. You found Giesel grazing peacefully in a small glade, and were able to bring her back to Laidulf without either of you being eaten by wolves.
x2tagx2sq17_Desc_E=A panicked man called Laidulf was missing what turned out to be a sheep that ran off into the woods. Unfortunately you were not able to prevent his fears from coming true, and the wolves made short work of his dear Giesel. All that was left was her pelt, which Laidulf received with tearful eyes.
x2tagx2sq17_Desc_F=A panicked man called Laidulf was missing what turned out to be a sheep that ran off into the woods. Unfortunately you were not able to prevent his fears from coming true, and the wolves made short work of his dear Giesel. You gave him a necklace made of wolf claws as proof that Giesel had been avenged, which consoled him a bit.
x2tagGiesel_A1=Baaa…
x2taggylfi_giesel=Giesel ~ Sheep
x2tagx2sq18_Title=The Spectral Wolf
x2tagx2sq18_Desc_A=A ghostly wolf has appeared in the forests of Scandia, attacking everyone who crosses its path. One of the local mystics might know more about it.
x2tagx2sq18_Desc_B=A ghostly wolf has appeared in the forests of Scandia, attacking everyone who crosses its path. The mysterious Völva Gyda knew about a great wolf who is said to be the son of Fafnir. Search for 'what remains' of it in the local caves.
x2tagx2sq18_Desc_C=A ghostly wolf has appeared in the forests of Scandia, attacking everyone who crosses its path. You have found the skull of the old Alpha deep inside the wolves' lair. With it in your possession, you may be able to defeat the ghost.
x2tagx2sq18_Desc_D=A ghost wolf haunted the forests of Scandia, attacking everyone who crossed its path. You retrieved the skull of the old Alpha and used it to bind and defeat its ghost, so no one will be bothered by it ever again. Talk to Gyda.
x2tagx2sq18_Desc_E=A ghost wolf haunted the forests of Scandia, attacking everyone who crossed its path. You retrieved the skull of the old Alpha and used it to bind and defeat its ghost, so no one will be bothered by it ever again.
x2tagx2sq19_Title=Squabbling Merchants
x2tagx2sq19_Desc_A=Two stubborn brothers both claim a house at the marketplace of Kaupangr. Ulfgrim is determined to have it remain a weapons forge while Tryggbord wants to use it to sell armor. Help them settle the disagreement.
x2tagx2sq19_Desc_B=Two stubborn brothers both claim a house at the marketplace of Kaupangr. Ulfgrim is determined to have it remain a weapons forge while Tryggbord wants to use it to sell armor. You have received a letter of ownership for the house from the chieftess. Give the permit to either Ulfgrim or Tryggbord.
x2tagx2sq19_Desc_C=Two stubborn brothers both claimed a house at the marketplace of Kaupangr. Ulfgrim was determined to have it remain a weapons forge while Tryggbord wanted to use it to sell armor. You settled the debate by acquiring a letter of ownership from the chieftess.
x2tagx2sq19_Desc_C1=Two stubborn brothers both claimed a house at the marketplace of Kaupangr. Ulfgrim was determined to have it remain a weapons forge while Tryggbord wanted to use it to sell armor. You helped Tryggbord to his right as the older heir by acquiring a letter of ownership from the chieftess.
x2tagx2sq19_Desc_C2=Two stubborn brothers both claimed a house at the marketplace of Kaupangr. Ulfgrim was determined to have it remain a weapons forge while Tryggbord wanted to use it to sell armor. You helped Ulfgrim honor their father's legacy by acquiring a letter of ownership from the chieftess.
x2tagx2sq20_Title=The Craftman's Passion
x2tagx2sq20_Desc_A=The grumpy trapper Bjarni asked you about Lupine Claws, which he apparently needs for his craft. If you have any, maybe he would tell you what this is about.
x2tagx2sq20_Desc_B=The grumpy trapper Bjarni seems to have a hidden artistic side, and asked about Lupine Claws for his latest design of a necklace. When you actually had some he claimed to have already moved on to something else, but was happy to share his sketches.
x2tagx2sq21_Title=Dvergar History
x2tagx2sq21_Desc_A=Valdis, the Spákona of Kaupangr, is researching the history of the Dvergr kingdom in order to find out more about its decline and curse. She asked you to look for any written records or items that might provide clues.
x2tagx2sq21_Desc_B=Valdis, the Spákona of Kaupangr, is researching the history of the Dvergr kingdom in order to find out more about its decline and curse. You were able to bring her the kind of runic record she was looking for, but half of it is still missing.
x2tagx2sq21_Desc_C=Valdis, the Spákona of Kaupangr, is researching the history of the Dvergr kingdom in order to find out more about its decline and curse. You were able to bring her a complete runic tablet to study, for which she was very grateful.
x2tagx2sq22_Title=Legendary Craftsmanship
x2tagx2sq22_Desc_A=The Dvergr master smiths Durin and Dvalin offer to look into upgrading your equipment if you bring them some fine mead: The mead of the Einherjar, from the udder of Heidrun.
x2tagx2sq22_Desc_B=The Dvergr master smiths Durin and Dvalin offer to look into upgrading your equipment if you bring them some fine mead.  You found what they are asking for deep in the halls of Valhöll. Take the mead to Durin.
x2tagx2sq22_Desc_C=After receiving the mead, the Dvergr smiths Durin and Dvalin agreed to help you and upgrade a piece of  Epic or Legendary gear, but now they want more mead as payment for the actual work: The famed Mead of Poetry.
x2tagx2sq22_Desc_D=The Dvergr master smiths Durin and Dvalin agreed to help you and upgrade a piece of  Epic or Legendary gear, but they want more mead as payment for the actual work. You found the Mead of Poetry high up on the Hnitbjorg mountains. Take the mead to Durin.
x2tagx2sq22_Desc_E=The Dvergr master smiths Durin and Dvalin are now finally willing to upgrade a piece of  your unique gear, but they are lacking a crucial ingredient they need to actually do it. Find Blacksteel.
x2tagx2sq22_Desc_F=The Dvergr master smiths Durin and Dvalin are now finally willing to upgrade a piece of  your unique gear, but they were lacking a crucial ingredient they need to actually do it. Bring the Blacksteel you found in Surtr's fortress to Durin.
x2tagx2sq22_Desc_G=The Dvergr master smiths Durin and Dvalin offered to upgrade a piece of Epic or Legendary gear. With all the mead they wanted in their bellies and the Blacksteel in hand Durin and Dvalin would finally forge you some mighty equipment.
x2tagHeidrun_A1=Baaa…
x2tagQuestRegionSQ01=Corinth
x2tagQuestRegionSQ02=Corinth
x2tagQuestRegionSQ03=Corinth
x2tagQuestRegionSQ04=Heuneburg
x2tagQuestRegionSQ05=Heuneburg
x2tagQuestRegionSQ06=Heuneburg
x2tagQuestRegionSQ07=Glauberg
x2tagQuestRegionSQ08=Glauberg
x2tagQuestRegionSQ09=Glauberg
x2tagQuestRegionSQ10=Wildlands
x2tagQuestRegionSQ11=Wildlands
x2tagQuestRegionSQ12=Wildlands
x2tagQuestRegionSQ13=Scandia
x2tagQuestRegionSQ14=Scandia
x2tagQuestRegionSQ15=Scandia
x2tagQuestRegionSQ16=Scandia
x2tagQuestRegionSQ17=Scandia
x2tagQuestRegionSQ18=Scandia
x2tagQuestRegionSQ19=Dark Lands
x2tagQuestRegionSQ20=Dark Lands
x2tagQuestRegionSQ21=Dark Lands
x2tagQuestRegionSQ22=Dark Lands
x2tagQuestRegionSQ23=Jotunheim
x2tagQuestRegionSQ24=Jotunheim
